<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>coffee on Yo-Dave</title>
    <link>https://yo-dave.com/tags/coffee/</link>
    <description>Recent content in coffee on Yo-Dave</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2011-2018, David D. Clark. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 09:44:34 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yo-dave.com/tags/coffee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Coffee Roasters</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2018/07/14/the-best-coffee-roasters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 09:44:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2018/07/14/the-best-coffee-roasters/</guid>
      <description>There was an article that I came across recently that listed the 25 &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; coffee roasters in America. The report included lots of companies I had never heard of and only a few of the ones I believe rank up there with the best.
As you may know, I have some opinions about coffee, mostly that it is about flavor, not caffeine. Also, I strongly prefer specific methods of preparation to others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffee Storage</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/09/12/coffee-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/09/12/coffee-storage/</guid>
      <description>I know, this is quite a &amp;ldquo;First World&amp;rdquo; kind of problem isn&#39;t it. Nevertheless&amp;hellip;
As I&#39;ve written before, I like coffee. I probably spend too much on the beans as well. So, there is a need to store them correctly to maintain the best flavor for as long as possible.
The Problem Coffee has three major enemies:
 Light Air (specifically, the oxygen in the air) Moisture  There&#39;s also one more wrinkle to deal with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Drink Coffee Because it Tastes Good</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2015/05/10/i-drink-coffee-because-it-tastes-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2015/05/10/i-drink-coffee-because-it-tastes-good/</guid>
      <description>Seems like there have been a lot of posts recently about folks using coffee to optimize their energy or alertness levels. That’s just trying to use coffee as some sort of mind-altering drug. That’s wrong. You should drink coffee because you think it tastes good. That’s why I drink it.
How I Got Here Like most people, I was introduced to coffee by my parents. They drank it and I watched.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>