<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogging on Yo-Dave</title>
    <link>https://yo-dave.com/categories/blogging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogging on Yo-Dave</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2011-2020, David D. Clark. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 10:09:24 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yo-dave.com/categories/blogging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Blogging Setup</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2018/03/26/new-blogging-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 10:09:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2018/03/26/new-blogging-setup/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a bit of a slog, but things should be up and running again. The transition was a bit harder than expected.
Here are some things you should know:
 The site is generated by the Hugo static site generator. The site uses a trivial modification of the very pleasant Blackburn theme. There are still some kinks I want to work out, but it is very useful overall. The repository for the site is on GitHub here and is generated from the information in the repository here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So Many Broken Links</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2018/03/17/so-many-broken-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 13:24:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2018/03/17/so-many-broken-links/</guid>
      <description>As noted in yesterday&amp;rsquo;s blog, I&amp;rsquo;m making a sweep through my previous posts trying to fix links that have broken over the years. This is in preparation for switching to another blogging platform.
I find that the rot even creeps into the README.md files in my own code repositories. Many of them refer back to descriptions of the repositories posted to no longer existing versions of the blog.
I&amp;rsquo;ll fix those as soon as I can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bit Rot</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2018/03/16/bit-rot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 09:41:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2018/03/16/bit-rot/</guid>
      <description>Every once in awhile, I change blogging platforms. Recently I have been working on a switch to Hugo. Whenever I go through this exercise, I religiously check for broken links. There are always plenty.
Most of the time, when broken links are found, I can find a replacement. Sometimes not though. Sometimes something is just gone. No new address. No record in the Internet Archive Wayback Machine. Just gone.
I know I&amp;rsquo;m contributing to this myself by changing hosts and blogging platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proofreading: I am Humbled</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2017/08/25/proofreading-i-am-humbled/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 14:15:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2017/08/25/proofreading-i-am-humbled/</guid>
      <description>Often, when reading blogs, I am struck by the number of misspellings, incorrect word usages, bad grammar, and so on.
But the experience of transferring this blog from other systems to it&amp;rsquo;s current home has been an eye opener. I proofread my posts, usually multiple times. However, in doing so I was struck by the number of misspellings, incorrect word usages, bad grammar, and so on.
I am humbled (in the real sense of the word.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No More Disqus</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2015/05/15/no-more-disqus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 17:09:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2015/05/15/no-more-disqus/</guid>
      <description>Man, I am so fed up with companies that insist on tracking me. Disqus has a great commenting system. Great features. Widely used.
But they track you, building a pretty detailed profile, which they sell. They do it to both me and you if you comment on this site. Without telling either of us. So, Disqus is out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Theme</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2014/04/30/a-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 09:59:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2014/04/30/a-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>This probably has no interest to anyone but me, but you may notice a change in the blog theme today. I&amp;rsquo;ve been dissatisfied with the typography of the blog for quite some time. Today I set out to try to find a theme that had better typography. Man, what a mess!
There are a zillion WordPress themes out there. Some awful, but many quite good. However, finding a minimalist theme intended for writing and reading is surprisingly difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Something New. Comments!</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2014/03/26/something-new.-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 13:33:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2014/03/26/something-new.-comments/</guid>
      <description>Well, it&amp;rsquo;s been a long time coming and I&amp;rsquo;m still a little unsure about it, but starting now, this site will allow comments. I&amp;rsquo;ve explained why I didn&amp;rsquo;t allow them before, but I&amp;rsquo;m adding Disqus-powered discussions to the blog. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how that goes.
If everything that comes in is just spam, I&amp;rsquo;ll disable comments again. If comments are useful, civil and on topic, they will remain.
And we&amp;rsquo;ll see if anyone thinks any of this stuff is interesting enough to comment on in the first place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why No Comments?</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/03/18/why-no-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 17:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/03/18/why-no-comments/</guid>
      <description>There are two primary reasons that comments are not enabled on this site.
 These are just notes I write to myself. They don&amp;rsquo;t get much attention other than when I want to remind myself of something. It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be fair to solicit comments and then just ignore them. Comment spam. Related to the above, I just don&amp;rsquo;t check in often enough and would not effectively moderate and eliminate spam.  This does not mean that the site will never be opened up to comments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syntax Highlighting</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/01/30/syntax-highlighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2011 01:11:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/01/30/syntax-highlighting/</guid>
      <description>Update 2017-08-19: This post refers to a time when the blog was hosted in WordPress. It isn&amp;rsquo;t really applicable anymore. But it may provide some guidance to someone who happens to come across it.
Since this blog is mostly about programming, there are a lot of code listings. To make those listings more easily readable, highlighting syntax in the listings is a good thing.
Of all of the syntax highlighters I have tried, the SyntaxHighlighter JavaScript tool by Alex Gorbachev is the one I most prefer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving Old Posts</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/01/23/moving-old-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2011 00:56:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/01/23/moving-old-posts/</guid>
      <description>Since I&amp;rsquo;m going through the setup again, I thought I would start out with some older posts from other systems (the few that remain). Don&amp;rsquo;t pay much attention to the dates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So, Dr. Clark. We meet again!</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/01/22/so-dr.-clark.-we-meet-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 23:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/01/22/so-dr.-clark.-we-meet-again/</guid>
      <description>Well, here we are again. You, me, and WordPress. It seems like I go through this setup a lot. Over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried other blogging platforms, and even toyed with the idea of creating one of my own for fun like one of my heroes, Brian Carper(Broken Link). But I just keep coming back here. Why do I ever leave?
There are really a couple of reasons. I do this a lot because of hardware and backup failures.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
