<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yo-Dave</title>
    <link>https://yo-dave.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Yo-Dave</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2011-2018, David D. Clark. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 12:10:31 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yo-dave.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Remote Repositories for Mercurial</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2019/08/25/setting-up-remote-repositories-for-mercurial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 12:10:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2019/08/25/setting-up-remote-repositories-for-mercurial/</guid>
      <description>With the recent announcement that Bitbucket is &amp;ldquo;sunsetting&amp;rdquo; Mercurial support, I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at ways of hosting remote copies of my repositories on my own.
In the short term, I have just cloned my repositories from Bitbucket onto a Raspberry Pi 4 sitting behind my home desktop. I use Pi to run a River of News aggregator for my family. It has plenty of capacity for a task like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letting the User Change the Sidebar Width in CWiki</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2019/06/27/letting-the-user-change-the-sidebar-width-in-cwiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 16:51:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2019/06/27/letting-the-user-change-the-sidebar-width-in-cwiki/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on what I thought was a simple feature &amp;ndash; changing the width of the sidebar in the CWiki wiki program.
There were two ways the user could do it.
First, they could set it manually in the &amp;ldquo;Preferences&amp;rdquo; page.
Second, and more naturally in my opinion, they could use the mouse to drag the separator between the sidebar and the main article area to the location they wanted it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting from a Web Client Whether a Particular Font is Installed</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2019/06/03/detecting-from-a-web-client-whether-a-particular-font-is-installed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 17:31:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2019/06/03/detecting-from-a-web-client-whether-a-particular-font-is-installed/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, a web client just needs to know what font it is using. The use cases may vary, but when you need it, you need it.
In my own case, I have a tag editing component for my personal wiki. The component allows entry of any number of tags. It also changes the size of the input as the user types in the text, getting smaller when characters are deleted or larger when new characters are entered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Displaying Video from a Webcam using Clojurescript and Reagent</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2019/05/13/displaying-video-from-a-webcam-using-clojurescript-and-reagent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 08:22:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2019/05/13/displaying-video-from-a-webcam-using-clojurescript-and-reagent/</guid>
      <description>As part of a book cataloging project, I want to be able to use a webcam on a desktop or laptop to scan ISBN (International Standard Book Number) numbers from the jackets of physical books. This isn&amp;rsquo;t quite as easy as scanning barcodes with a phone or tablet because of focus, magnification, and depth of field characteristics of desktop and laptop cameras. (Or so I&amp;rsquo;m told. I really don&amp;rsquo;t know much about it yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wiki Layout for Editing</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2018/10/23/wiki-layout-for-editing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 16:05:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2018/10/23/wiki-layout-for-editing/</guid>
      <description>Update: 2018-12-15 This post substantially updates the original. The most significant changes are that the layout now works as expected - no partial success.
A few weeks ago, I wrote a post about a wiki layout for reading. I used that project to experiment with improvements to the reading view of CWiki, a personal wiki that I am writing. I used the lessons learned in the project described in that post to make some changes to CWiki.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wiki Layout for Reading</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2018/09/23/wiki-layout-for-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 13:20:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2018/09/23/wiki-layout-for-reading/</guid>
      <description>​As many of you know, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a personal wiki for some time now. (See the CWiki repository.) In fact, I&amp;rsquo;m using it to write this post. It&amp;rsquo;s very comfortable for me.
One of the things I have been trying to get absolutely right (for me at least) is the layout. There are really only two layouts; one is for the &amp;ldquo;reading&amp;rdquo; view, the other for the &amp;ldquo;editing&amp;rdquo; view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing a flexmark Extension in Clojure</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2018/09/16/writing-a-flexmark-extension-in-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 10:10:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2018/09/16/writing-a-flexmark-extension-in-clojure/</guid>
      <description>Writing wiki pages using Markdown is a great way to do things because it is simple, well-known, and capable.
One of the annoyances of using Markdown is that it has no default syntax to create wikilinks, a type of hyperlink that links one page in a wiki to another.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a home-grown, personal wiki, CWiki, for almost a year now off and on. It&amp;rsquo;s written in the Clojure programming language, which is a pleasure to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuart Sierras Component System</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2018/08/13/stuart-sierras-component-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 15:34:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2018/08/13/stuart-sierras-component-system/</guid>
      <description>Starting the implementation of user options (preferences) in CWiki (a personal wiki program) got me thinking about refactoring the project into a shape that is more compatible with Stuart Sierras reloaded workflow. Naturally, that led to thinking about his component architecture. Here are some more resources related to the component architecture.
 Stuart has a blog post about his reloaded workflow, linked above. The component code repository is on Github here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>De-Tabifying</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2018/08/12/de-tabifying/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 13:36:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2018/08/12/de-tabifying/</guid>
      <description>There is probably no more boring task in programming than processing a file to replace tabs with spaces or doing the reverse and replacing spaces with tabs. And yet it has started religious wars that have raged for years in various programming communities.
This &amp;ldquo;tabifying&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;de-tabifying&amp;rdquo; is not something I have to do frequently, but every once in a while, I need to convert tabs to spaces in some text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autosave Functionality in ClojureScript</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2018/08/01/autosave-functionality-in-clojurescript/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 15:56:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2018/08/01/autosave-functionality-in-clojurescript/</guid>
      <description>Most programs provide an &amp;ldquo;Autosave&amp;rdquo; feature these days. The feature gives the user a chance to minimize the amount of work lost due to some unforeseen mishap, like a sudden power outage.
When I write a program in Clojure that requires such a feature, I have the entire Java library at my disposal. I usually create something based on a ScheduledExecutorService &amp;ndash; something that watches for a change in the document then allows a certain amount of user inactivity to pass before automatically saving the document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note-Taking</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2018/07/15/note-taking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 16:47:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2018/07/15/note-taking/</guid>
      <description>Changing jobs in 2005 caused me to switch from taking notes on paper to doing it electronically.
My new employer provided a tablet PC with a stylus running Windows and OneNote. Taking notes on that system with excellent handwriting recognition was a revelation. The tablet was pretty clunky by today&amp;rsquo;s standards, but it worked well. It was particularly useful for generating meeting notes in real time and projecting them during meetings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving Away from Collate Notes</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2018/07/14/moving-away-from-collate-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 10:07:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2018/07/14/moving-away-from-collate-notes/</guid>
      <description>Collate Notes has received my praise in the past. I even paid for it. Shortly after that unusual event, development seems to have stopped. And it still has numerous shortcomings. The most annoying problem is that periodically, it says my trial period has run out, and I need to enter the activation code (again). And since it&amp;rsquo;s closed-source, I have no recourse but to submit bugs and make feature requests to a developer who seems to have gone silent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Coffee Roasters</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2018/07/14/the-best-coffee-roasters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 09:44:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2018/07/14/the-best-coffee-roasters/</guid>
      <description>There was an article that I came across recently that listed the 25 &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; coffee roasters in America. The report included lots of companies I had never heard of and only a few of the ones I believe rank up there with the best.
As you may know, I have some opinions about coffee, mostly that it is about flavor, not caffeine. Also, I strongly prefer specific methods of preparation to others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Caddy Server as a Proxy for a Web App using Sente WebSockets</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2018/07/04/using-caddy-server-as-a-proxy-for-a-web-app-using-sente-websockets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 09:49:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2018/07/04/using-caddy-server-as-a-proxy-for-a-web-app-using-sente-websockets/</guid>
      <description>I created a simple web app, called clajistan.
Purpose The purpose of creating the app was two-fold.
 I wanted to have a little app to act as a &amp;ldquo;placeholder&amp;rdquo; on a very lightly used virtual server. To learn how to use WebSockets (sente) behind a proxy server (Caddy).  Desired Performance The program displays a simple web page, written in ClojureScript, with a few statistics about the server, written in Clojure:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Closing Branches in Mercurial</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2018/06/09/closing-branches-in-mercurial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 16:47:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2018/06/09/closing-branches-in-mercurial/</guid>
      <description>As a lone developer, I have a workflow that I believe is pretty typical.
Most of my development work happens on the &amp;ldquo;tip&amp;rdquo; of the &amp;ldquo;default&amp;rdquo; branch. It&amp;rsquo;s just easier to do work on fixing small bugs or adding minor features there.
For more significant, more difficult pieces of work, I usually create a &amp;ldquo;feature branch.&amp;rdquo; I do this with the expectation that if things get messed up too badly, I can delete the branch and start over without affecting the readiness of the default branch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CWiki-Next</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2018/05/01/cwiki-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 09:38:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2018/05/01/cwiki-next/</guid>
      <description>For the past few months, I&amp;rsquo;ve been beating my head against a brick wall. The problem was that I was trying to get an all-server-side wiki built using Clojure.
It actually works pretty well. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it for personal information for months now. It works well except for one aspect, arguably the most important &amp;ndash; editing new or existing content is not that pleasant.
It&amp;rsquo;s all a variation of Markdown, which is nice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on ClojureScript Regular Expressions</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2018/04/20/notes-on-clojurescript-regular-expressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 10:14:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2018/04/20/notes-on-clojurescript-regular-expressions/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s an old saying about regular expressions &amp;ndash; paraphrasing: &amp;ldquo;If you try to solve a problem with regular expressions, you then have two problems.&amp;rdquo;
Even though regular expressions are present in most programming languages, I have never become particularly proficient with them. Those that I am most familiar with are the Java version. Since ClojureScript compiles to JavaScript and runs without the Java underpinnings, it&amp;rsquo;s version of regular expressions are different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Anonymous Functions in the Clojure/Script Thrush Macro</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2018/04/15/using-anonymous-functions-in-the-clojure/script-thrush-macro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 11:48:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2018/04/15/using-anonymous-functions-in-the-clojure/script-thrush-macro/</guid>
      <description>The other day, I was putting together a sequence of operations to transform one piece of text into another form of that same text. The functions took a text argument, and the result was a slightly tweaked version. Put all those functions together to get the fully transformed result.
What could be more natural than to string those pieces of code together with one of Clojure&amp;rsquo;s threading macros: &amp;lsquo;-&amp;gt;&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restart River5 after Reboot with PM2</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2018/03/28/restart-river5-after-reboot-with-pm2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 10:06:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2018/03/28/restart-river5-after-reboot-with-pm2/</guid>
      <description>I run a River5 &amp;ldquo;River of News&amp;rdquo; on a Raspberry Pi wirelessly connected to my internal home network. Sometimes, the power fluctuates, and the Pi reboots. I want to have River5 restart when the system comes back up.
There are lots of ways to restart stuff on Linux. (I am running Raspian GNU/Linux 8.0.) The process manager I use is PM2 &amp;ndash; mostly because it knows Nodejs. River5 is written for Node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Blogging Setup</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2018/03/26/new-blogging-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 10:09:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2018/03/26/new-blogging-setup/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a bit of a slog, but things should be up and running again. The transition was a bit harder than expected.
Here are some things you should know:
 The site is generated by the Hugo static site generator. The site uses a trivial modification of the very pleasant Blackburn theme. There are still some kinks I want to work out, but it is very useful overall. The repository for the site is on GitHub here and is generated from the information in the repository here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So Many Broken Links</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2018/03/17/so-many-broken-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 13:24:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2018/03/17/so-many-broken-links/</guid>
      <description>As noted in yesterday&amp;rsquo;s blog, I&amp;rsquo;m making a sweep through my previous posts trying to fix links that have broken over the years. This is in preparation for switching to another blogging platform.
I find that the rot even creeps into the README.md files in my own code repositories. Many of them refer back to descriptions of the repositories posted to no longer existing versions of the blog.
I&amp;rsquo;ll fix those as soon as I can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bit Rot</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2018/03/16/bit-rot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 09:41:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2018/03/16/bit-rot/</guid>
      <description>Every once in awhile, I change blogging platforms. Recently I have been working on a switch to Hugo. Whenever I go through this exercise, I religiously check for broken links. There are always plenty.
Most of the time, when broken links are found, I can find a replacement. Sometimes not though. Sometimes something is just gone. No new address. No record in the Internet Archive Wayback Machine. Just gone.
I know I&amp;rsquo;m contributing to this myself by changing hosts and blogging platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Information</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/contact/contact-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 17:32:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/contact/contact-information/</guid>
      <description>This is some contact information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Information</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/contact/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 17:32:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/contact/contact/</guid>
      <description>If you are trying to contact me, you will have a hard time at the moment. I don&amp;rsquo;t use social media. And I&amp;rsquo;m fiddling with different email services right now. And I don&amp;rsquo;t usually check my email very often. May clear this up later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About This Blog</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 17:31:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/about/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! My name is David Clark (one of many, I’m afraid.)
This site is just a place for me to write down things I find interesting or to capture notes about things I’m likely to forget.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been blogging for awhile. I&amp;rsquo;ve used a lot of blogging software and hosted things in many places. This site consolidates those posts back to 2011. Since things came here from multiple other blogs, you might see multiple posts talking about the same thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Timestamp Plugin for Sublime Text 3</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2018/02/10/a-timestamp-plugin-for-sublime-text-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 10:16:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2018/02/10/a-timestamp-plugin-for-sublime-text-3/</guid>
      <description>Since switching from Windows to a Mac in the middle of developing a new wiki, I lost access to the MarkdownPad Markdown editor &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s Windows only. One of the nice features of MarkdownPad was the ability to insert a timestamp easily. It&amp;rsquo;s what I used to insert the creation date and the time of the last modification.
Since the switch, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Sublime Text 3 as my editor for Markdown files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Useful Function -- convert-seq-to-comma-separated-string</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2018/01/19/another-useful-function-convert-seq-to-comma-separated-string/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 14:32:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2018/01/19/another-useful-function-convert-seq-to-comma-separated-string/</guid>
      <description>This is a little note about a function I find myself using frequently in Clojure.
User interface code often needs to display a list of things as a comma-separated list, e.g. &amp;ldquo;a, b, c, d&amp;rdquo;.
If all of the things are strings, you can use the built-in string/join function to build such a string. When you have a sequence of things that are not strings, I suppose you could convert each element to a string and then use string/join.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sorted-set-by</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2018/01/19/sorted-set-by/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 13:49:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2018/01/19/sorted-set-by/</guid>
      <description>This is just a little note about one of my favorite datatypes in Clojure.
Like most Lisps, Clojure has a very useful group of datatypes built in including some set types. I use sorted-set a lot. Until recently, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t noticed sorted-set-by, a function that returns a sorted set using a comparator you specify. I found myself needing to create a sorted set of strings where the sorting was case-insensitive. The sorted-set-by function was exactly what I needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Version of the Confidence Interval Program</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2017/09/13/a-new-version-of-the-confidence-interval-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 17:18:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2017/09/13/a-new-version-of-the-confidence-interval-program/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I wrote about updating an old program that did the Sign Test. Well, I have lots of old programs that could stand a bit of refreshing.
Another of the simple ones calculates the confidence interval around the proportion of successes in a series of Bernoulli trials. I wrote about it way back in 2011. The original was written in Java and Swing many years ago. It is still available in a repository on Bitbucket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spell Checking in the Editor Changes the Way I Name Things</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2017/08/31/spell-checking-in-the-editor-changes-the-way-i-name-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 14:16:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2017/08/31/spell-checking-in-the-editor-changes-the-way-i-name-things/</guid>
      <description>While editing some program text recently, I noticed myself doing something weird. I do most of my programming in Clojure these days. I mostly use IntelliJ IDEA with the Cursive plugin for Clojure. This turns out to be a great way to develop.
One of the (many) things I love about IntelliJ IDEA is that it does spell checking in my code. Stops me looking (so much) like an idiot when I misspell stuff in comments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Titled JavaFX Separator</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2017/08/31/a-titled-javafx-separator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 13:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2017/08/31/a-titled-javafx-separator/</guid>
      <description>In the process of updating some old programs, I had to change the GUI frameworks used. The old programs were written in Java using the Swing GUI framework and the JGoodies Forms and Looks libraries. Nowadays, the official GUI framework for Java is JavaFX.
Making the transition from Swing to JavaFX was relatively painless because the programs were so small. However, one of the things I missed from the JGoodies Forms library was the &amp;ldquo;titled separator&amp;rdquo;, that is a separator with a label in front of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Updated Sign Test Program</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2017/08/31/an-updated-sign-test-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 13:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2017/08/31/an-updated-sign-test-program/</guid>
      <description>Long ago, I wrote a post about a small program to calculate the probabilities of a sign test.
A lot has happened since then.
The sign test is still useful to me on occasion, but the application framework used to write the original program is now unsupported. Too, the original program used Java&amp;rsquo;s Swing framework for the GUI. The new official GUI framework for Java is JavaFX.
So I&amp;rsquo;ve updated the program a bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proofreading: I am Humbled</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2017/08/25/proofreading-i-am-humbled/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 14:15:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2017/08/25/proofreading-i-am-humbled/</guid>
      <description>Often, when reading blogs, I am struck by the number of misspellings, incorrect word usages, bad grammar, and so on.
But the experience of transferring this blog from other systems to it&amp;rsquo;s current home has been an eye opener. I proofread my posts, usually multiple times. However, in doing so I was struck by the number of misspellings, incorrect word usages, bad grammar, and so on.
I am humbled (in the real sense of the word.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Images to Load and Preview in Hexo</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2017/08/20/getting-images-to-load-and-preview-in-hexo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 13:55:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2017/08/20/getting-images-to-load-and-preview-in-hexo/</guid>
      <description>As part of the work of transferring old blog posts from other systems (mostly WordPress) to Hexo, I hit a bump when trying to use images in the new posts.
There are basically two recommended ways to access images in Hexo.
 Put a new sub-directory, say images in your Hexo source directory. Put your images in your new directory. In your posts, use the usual Markdown method of linking to images, that is something like !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turns Out My Hosting Company **was** a Scam</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2017/08/16/turns-out-my-hosting-company-was-a-scam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 13:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2017/08/16/turns-out-my-hosting-company-was-a-scam/</guid>
      <description>Way back in 2014, I wrote a post asking whether my new hosting company, CloudAtCost was a scam. Back then, I concluded that they were not.
Fast forward to now, and it turns out they were a scam after all.
Back in June they started sending me notices about not having paid a fee for &amp;ldquo;Maintenance&amp;rdquo;. They threatened to shut down and erase all my stuff at some unspecified time in the near future if I didn&amp;rsquo;t pay up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Light</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2017/08/15/first-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 14:03:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2017/08/15/first-light/</guid>
      <description>First light with a new blogging platform.
My hosting vendors have been playing games with me. They offer terrific prices to new customers to start using them. But the loyal folks who have been using them for years get nothing &amp;ndash; except maybe a price increase. Not cool.
So, I&amp;rsquo;m looking into hosting my blog for free on GitHub Pages. It even provides HTTPS out of the box. No configuring certificates or any of that stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Note-Taking Goodness - Collate</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2017/05/16/more-note-taking-goodness-collate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2017/05/16/more-note-taking-goodness-collate/</guid>
      <description>Last time, I wrote about some of the really nice note-taking apps available nowadays. Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve come across another great one I just had to tell you about: Collate.
It has just about everything I could want. I&amp;rsquo;ll let you read about all of its features on its web site, but some of the things I like most include:
 It&amp;rsquo;s cross-platform, capable of running on Windows, MacOS, and Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leiningen passing Invalid Flags to Java Compiler</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2017/05/14/leiningen-passing-invalid-flags-to-java-compiler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 09:54:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2017/05/14/leiningen-passing-invalid-flags-to-java-compiler/</guid>
      <description>Just a note about some weirdness in my work process and it&amp;#8217;s solution.
A few weeks ago, I started noticing some weirdness in trying to use some tools with Leiningen while developing a program in Clojure. When running tools like kibit, lein would fail with an error from javac about an invalid flag. Initially these flags were for attempts to set the file encoding. And the file encoding kept changing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rant About JavaFX Ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2017/04/22/rant-about-javafx-ecosystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2017 14:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2017/04/22/rant-about-javafx-ecosystem/</guid>
      <description>Feeling a bit frustrated today, so I thought I would just vent a bit.
I&amp;#8217;ve been working on some personal tools. I see some things in other tools that I would like to include in my own. I keep finding that those features that I like are written in JavaScript with that whole mess of an ecosystem. When I look for something similar in Java/JavaFX I find next to nothing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Embarrassment of Riches for Note-Taking</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2017/04/03/an-embarrassment-of-riches-for-note-taking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2017/04/03/an-embarrassment-of-riches-for-note-taking/</guid>
      <description>Ever since dumping Evernote, I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at alternative note-taking apps. I&amp;rsquo;ve been usingtiddlywiki, but, surprisingly, it has grown a bit slow. Probably from the sheer volume of notes that I&amp;rsquo;ve imported from Evernote. Maybe time to look some more?
I&amp;rsquo;ve also been writing a lot of program documentation in Markdown. I like the wiki format just fine, but it seems like Markdown can do more. Both markup languages have a plethora of dialects, usually incompatible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vendor Games with Subscriptions</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2017/03/04/vendor-games-with-subscriptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2017/03/04/vendor-games-with-subscriptions/</guid>
      <description>I have subscriptions to a number of services, not just magazines. These include things like computer programs, hosting services, home supplies, groceries and so on. I&amp;rsquo;m sure vendors love this.
Within the past two weeks though, I have canceled three subscriptions when the vendor started playing games at renewal time. It usually went down like this:
 I get notification of a renewal at an (often substantially) increased price. Increases of 30%+ are not uncommon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Whinging about CloudAtCost</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2017/02/01/more-whinging-about-cloudatcost/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2017/02/01/more-whinging-about-cloudatcost/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written about my love/hate relationship with CloudAtCost before here and here. In essence, I like the low cost but hate the poor reliability.
At one time I had seven web sites up and running on servers bought from CloudAtCost, including this one. But over a period of weeks and months they all failed for one reason or another. Some of the failures could be fixed with a ticket to tech support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping the JavaFX UI Responsive</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2017/01/30/keeping-the-javafx-ui-responsive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 16:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2017/01/30/keeping-the-javafx-ui-responsive/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s common knowledge that the JavaFX user interface toolkit is single-threaded. When your JavaFX-based program is doing things that can take some time, you need to run those tasks on a separate thread(s) to keep the interface responsive.
Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a program that can spend a lot of time reading and writing to the disk, but at the same time I want to retain the ability for the user to change views of the UI as the work proceeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows, rsync and permissions</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/12/31/windows-rsync-and-permissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 10:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/12/31/windows-rsync-and-permissions/</guid>
      <description>Just a short note on mixing Linux utilities with Windows. I wanted to set up a single button deployment of updates to a static web site. I had been using an rsync script, but it required me to manually enter authentication credentials every time it was used to send updates to a remote Ubuntu server.
I set up public key authentication, but it would not work with the permissions of the key files on the Windows machine where the updates were coming from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>De-Activating My Evernote Account</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/12/16/de-activating-my-evernote-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 16:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/12/16/de-activating-my-evernote-account/</guid>
      <description>It was very unpleasant for me. I&amp;rsquo;ve been a user of Evernote almost from the beginning, and a Premium user for almost as long. But today I erased all of my notes and deactivated my account. &amp;ldquo;Why?&amp;rdquo; you might ask. Let me tell you.
 The price increase. Earlier in the Autumn, Evernote announced a price increase. It was pretty substantial, at least for me. At about the same time, they announced that they were moving our data to Google&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure in order to take advantage of improved economies of scale among other reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>De-Activating My Evernote Account</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/12/15/de-activating-my-evernote-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/12/15/de-activating-my-evernote-account/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m kind of sad today. I erased all of my notes from Evernote and then de-activated my account.
I had been a Premium user for years and had thousands of notes. I used it on the web (when using Linux), on the desktop under Windows, and on my iPhone and iPads. I liked that the data was available on all of those devices. I really liked the web clipper. But the killer feature that got me started on it in the first place was the ability to search in images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removing CDNs</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/12/10/removing-cdns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/12/10/removing-cdns/</guid>
      <description>(Update: 27 Mar 2018, Despite what the rest of this blog post says, I have reinstated CDNs. This site now uses the Cloudflare CDN due to the inability of raw GitHub Pages to serve sites with custom domain names over HTTPS. See this)
Everyone wants their web site to load quickly using as few resources as possible. Content Delivery Networks (CDNs) are a very attractive way to achieve this. You can put parts of your web site on someone else&amp;rsquo;s servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advertising at the Movies</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/12/09/advertising-at-the-movies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/12/09/advertising-at-the-movies/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, my wife and I went to the movies, something we don&amp;rsquo;t do very often. (Arrival, which I highly recommend, just like the short story it is derived from.)
We arrived at the theatre, one of those multi-screen megaplexes, about 15 to 20 minutes before the advertised start time for the feature. Of course, while waiting, we were exposed to the various advertisements shown before the start of the film.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why This Blog Disappeared for a Few Days</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/12/08/why-this-blog-disappeared-for-a-few-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/12/08/why-this-blog-disappeared-for-a-few-days/</guid>
      <description>Those of you who visit this site regularly may have noticed that is has been down for a few days. Here&amp;rsquo;s why.
About a week ago, I attempted to reboot the server after applying a few updates. It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t come back up. As I&amp;rsquo;ve written before, this site is hosted on CloudAtCost. Sorry to say that it is a regular occurrence for servers not to reboot.
Usually, I can just file a ticket and get help in a day or so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clojure/Script has Ruined Me for Other Languages</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/10/17/clojure/script-has-ruined-me-for-other-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 10:57:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/10/17/clojure/script-has-ruined-me-for-other-languages/</guid>
      <description>The Elm language is often cited as an up-and-comer for web front end development. I was attracted to it largely because of the compiler&amp;rsquo;s friendly and extremely helpful error messages. It&amp;rsquo;s really attractive in many ways.
But when I started looking at examples, I often found myself thinking things like &amp;ldquo;Why is this so inconsistent?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Why is this syntax so complicated?&amp;rdquo;. And it finally occurred to me that I&amp;rsquo;ve been ruined by the way Clojure/ClojureScript/Lisp/Scheme do things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Am So Over HD</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/10/02/i-am-so-over-hd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/10/02/i-am-so-over-hd/</guid>
      <description>Many years ago, back in 2009, during an infrequent upgrade of my desktop computer, I finally bought an HD monitor, actually, slightly better than HD at a resolution of 1920x1200 pixels. My reaction was along the lines of &amp;ldquo;Ooooh! Pretty!&amp;rdquo;. It was a big 27&amp;rdquo; unit. Easy to view, lots of screen real estate. Very clear text rendering.
I thought I was set forever.
Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve purchased a few Apple products with Retina displays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffee Storage</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/09/12/coffee-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/09/12/coffee-storage/</guid>
      <description>I know, this is quite a &amp;ldquo;First World&amp;rdquo; kind of problem isn&amp;rsquo;t it. Nevertheless&amp;hellip;
As I&amp;rsquo;ve written before, I like coffee. I probably spend too much on the beans as well. So, there is a need to store them correctly to maintain the best flavor for as long as possible.
The Problem Coffee has three major enemies:
 Light Air (specifically, the oxygen in the air) Moisture  There&amp;rsquo;s also one more wrinkle to deal with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Email Server on Ubuntu 14.04</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/08/26/an-email-server-on-ubuntu-14.04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 09:59:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/08/26/an-email-server-on-ubuntu-14.04/</guid>
      <description>Email is pretty old. It is older than the Internet. Despite the perennial claims that email is &amp;ldquo;dead&amp;rdquo;, it is still going strong. It&amp;rsquo;s also a bit complicated, which is why most folks set up an account with someone else (Yahoo!, Gmail, HotMail, ProtonMail, FastMail, etc.) who can take care of it for them.
However, if you want to host your own server, it can be done. If you are running Ubuntu 14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the Deal with Flash Sales?</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/08/26/whats-the-deal-with-flash-sales/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/08/26/whats-the-deal-with-flash-sales/</guid>
      <description>We have some pretty amazing communications technology these days. One way we seem to be wasting it is on the phenomenon of &amp;ldquo;Flash Sales&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; offering items on sale for a very short time. That&amp;rsquo;s all we need &amp;ndash; more advertising &amp;ndash; often for trivial discounts &amp;ndash; with deadline pressure.
I have never understood the allure of such things. It seems that people who have a &amp;ldquo;Fear of Missing Out&amp;rdquo; (FOMO) are most susceptible to this stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serving WordPress over HTTPS with Caddy Server</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/08/19/serving-wordpress-over-https-with-caddy-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 18:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/08/19/serving-wordpress-over-https-with-caddy-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://caddyserver.com/&#34;&gt;Caddy&lt;/a&gt; server is a relatively new, easy-to-use server written in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Go programming language&lt;/a&gt;. It is very buzzword compliant. But, the nicest thing about it, in my opinion, is that it sets up SSL/TLS (&lt;a href=&#34;http://info.ssl.com/article.aspx?id=10241&#34;&gt;Secure Sockets Layer&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transport_Layer_Security&#34;&gt;Transport Layer Security&lt;/a&gt;) certificates automatically from &lt;a href=&#34;https://letsencrypt.org/&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt&lt;/a&gt; to let you serve a site with&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTPS&#34;&gt; HTTPS&lt;/a&gt; by default. The project is open source and the certificates are free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/&#34;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; is a very popular blogging platform. Caddy provides some &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/caddyserver/examples/tree/master/wordpress&#34;&gt;guidance&lt;/a&gt; on getting WordPress up and running on the server. However, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough for me. Here&amp;rsquo;s some step-by-step guidance on how I got it working on some of my own self-hosted sites.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Font Pairings</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/08/17/font-pairings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/08/17/font-pairings/</guid>
      <description>As you may have guessed, I like to fiddle with things until they seem to be just perfect. One of those fiddly things is font pairing. (Changed them just today as a matter of fact.) I can never seem to get the perfect pairing of headline and body fonts.
In order to get a little more professional perspective, I follow the TypeWolf blog. Jeremiah Shoaf is a great design resource. I have even spent actual money to buy his &amp;ldquo;The Definitive Guide to Free Fonts&amp;rdquo;, which he updates monthly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Favorite Pens</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/08/13/my-favorite-pens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/08/13/my-favorite-pens/</guid>
      <description>Sure, this is a technology site, but sometimes you have to get a little retro. That is the case for my preferences in note-taking. I tend to do a fair amount of writing into paper notebooks. To do that, I use a pen.
Fountain pens are pretty pieces of art, but too messy and fiddly. Ballpoints are OK, but feel a little harsh as you write. Roller balls are OK too, except the quality of the ink is a bit &amp;ldquo;smeary&amp;rdquo; for my tastes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Server Setup Process</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/08/10/my-server-setup-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 15:58:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/08/10/my-server-setup-process/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://yo-dave.com/2016/02/12/2016-02-12-cloudatcost-setup-notes/&#34;&gt;Earlier&lt;/a&gt;, I posted about how I set up servers hosted at &lt;a href=&#34;http://cloudatcost.com/&#34;&gt;CloudAtCost&lt;/a&gt;. There have been a few changes to that process. Rather than continually patching that post, here&amp;#8217;s a new description. Again, this is for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntu.com/&#34;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; 14.04 which gets upgraded to 16.04 as part of the setup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caddy Server and Let&#39;s Encrypt</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/08/09/caddy-server-and-lets-encrypt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/08/09/caddy-server-and-lets-encrypt/</guid>
      <description>The observant among you may have noticed a small change in the blog. It&amp;rsquo;s that little lock symbol next to the URL for the post. That means the blog is being served on HTTPS instead of plain ol&amp;rsquo; HTTP.
Ever since hearing about it, I&amp;rsquo;ve had mixed feelings about the push to HTTPS. Of course, it will provide some benefit in terms of security. But if Google weights its search results based on whether or not a site supports it, access to some early web sites may be lost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speech Synthesis in ClojureScript</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/07/17/speech-synthesis-in-clojurescript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2016 12:35:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/07/17/speech-synthesis-in-clojurescript/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just like everyone else, it seems, I&amp;rsquo;ve been following all of the news about voice-activated personal assistants. There are all the commercial offerings like Siri, Alexa, Cortana, and so on, as well as some DIY projects on the web, like this &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.truthlabs.com/rethinking-voice-search-2496640fdec2#.uvnrkmji0&#34;&gt;one&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://howchoo.com/g/yti5mmq0ntu/add-voice-controls-to-your-raspberry-pi-using-jasper&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.instructables.com/id/Raspberri-Personal-Assistant/&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These types of projects typically involve a front end that converts voice to text, some middle piece that interprets the text and obtains some answer or creates an action, ending up with a voice response by the system back to the user. I have some (out-of-date) experience with speech to text, but not the other end of the process: text to speech. So here&amp;rsquo;s a little investigation into how to do it with ClojureScript. Turns out that it is almost trivial these days.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Desktop</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/07/06/the-linux-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/07/06/the-linux-desktop/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;ldquo;Linux Desktop&amp;rdquo; failing to gain traction is a perennial topic of blogs and musings by people smarter than me. But I&amp;rsquo;m going to offer my two cents worth of opinion anyway.
My Own Experience I use Linux on the desktop myself rather frequently, but it is not the OS my system boots to by default. Why is that?
Legacy Windows Programs It used to be that there was a large amount of inertia that kept me from making the switch completely because of legacy apps on Windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Experience with 1999 Blogging Software</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/06/05/my-experience-with-1999-blogging-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/06/05/my-experience-with-1999-blogging-software/</guid>
      <description>tldr; This long post contains my impressions of setting up and using the 1999.io blogging platform on a remote Ubuntu server.
Blogging is a great thing. It lets anybody say what they want to whatever audience is interested. It&amp;rsquo;s relatively simple for anyone to set up. (Me setting up this blog for example.) But it&amp;rsquo;s not dead simple. Particularly if you want to self-host your site rather than putting it on someone else&amp;rsquo;s machine, for example WordPress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon&#39;s non-Prime Shipping</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/05/12/amazons-non-prime-shipping/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 08:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/05/12/amazons-non-prime-shipping/</guid>
      <description>Since I&amp;rsquo;ve taken it upon myself to rail about Amazon&amp;rsquo;s behavior, here&amp;rsquo;s another thing.
Does Amazon actually delay delivery for it&amp;rsquo;s non-Prime customers? In the times I have not had a Prime account, it seems that orders are delayed in being filled on purpose. It seems like they make an effort to delay picking and filling the order, not really changing the shipping method itself.
This statement is based on two (unscientific) observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Day Shipping</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/05/12/two-day-shipping/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 08:40:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/05/12/two-day-shipping/</guid>
      <description>Is it just me or does it seem like the &amp;ldquo;FREE Two-Day Shipping&amp;rdquo; promised by Amazon Prime never actually occurs?
Sometimes I actually get things after one business day. But more often its three or four or five. Sometimes there&amp;rsquo;s an excuse like &amp;ldquo;Extreme Weather Conditions&amp;rdquo;. Sometimes things actually get here when promised.
If Amazon is paying extra for two day shipping, they are getting robbed.
Just sayin&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on NIH Syndrome</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/05/05/reflections-on-nih-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/05/05/reflections-on-nih-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>During the past few weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about &amp;ldquo;To Do&amp;rdquo; lists &amp;ndash; specifically how I wanted one. It was my plan to write my own, despite the fact that I have been using Evernote for years and that there are literally thousands already out there already. For the longest time, it never even occurred to me to use a manager that already existed. Or even just to use pen and paper for the simple lists I needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hardening an ngnx Server</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/04/28/hardening-an-ngnx-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/04/28/hardening-an-ngnx-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Besides the Clarkonium.net site where I host this blog, I have several other sites that I maintain. This is all more of an educational effort for myself than anything really important. That said, I am a neophyte in terms of server security. It&amp;rsquo;s something I want to do better. What better place to start than by evaluating security settings on some of my &amp;ldquo;play&amp;rdquo; sites that use &lt;a href=&#34;http://nginx.org&#34;&gt;nginx&lt;/a&gt; as the server component?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I said, I&amp;rsquo;m no expert, but these are some of the things I have done to my own sites.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Reasons to Dislike Blogs of Lists</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/04/28/three-reasons-to-dislike-blogs-of-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/04/28/three-reasons-to-dislike-blogs-of-lists/</guid>
      <description>Over the past few years, a lot of blogs or news articles have been written that are lists of items related to a larger topic, like &amp;ldquo;50 Ways to Leave Your Lover&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;10 Things You Didn&amp;rsquo;t Know about this Big Star&amp;rdquo; and so on.
I generally dislike these for three reasons.
 Lack of Speed. A lot of these articles are set up such that you have to load a sequence of pages to read each of the items.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cataract Surgery</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/04/20/cataract-surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/04/20/cataract-surgery/</guid>
      <description>Medical procedures are not always completely satisfactory. However, from my own experience, cataract surgery can be extremely beneficial.
Last year, vision in one of my eyes was becoming quite blurry. Vision in the other eye was deteriorating as well. I&amp;rsquo;ve known for years that I had small cataracts in one eye even though I am relatively young. (I blame chemotherapy several years ago, but who really knows.)
A visit to the ophthalmologist confirmed that my cataracts were growing rather quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Blogging Platform</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/04/12/a-new-blogging-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/04/12/a-new-blogging-platform/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;ldquo;Lou the Luddite&amp;rdquo; blog was originally created as a self-hosted WordPress blog. But this blog was always a bit problematic for some reason. At first, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get automatic WordPress updates to work. Then I found EasyEngine, which did the install for me and got things running. But it&amp;rsquo;s just a big black box of a script. I don&amp;rsquo;t know all of the details of what it does. That isn&amp;rsquo;t something I&amp;rsquo;m really comfortable with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ClojureScript with Reagent and figwheel</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/03/07/clojurescript-with-reagent-and-figwheel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/03/07/clojurescript-with-reagent-and-figwheel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a bit of a love/hate relationship with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/clojure/clojurescript&#34;&gt;ClojureScript&lt;/a&gt;. On the one hand, it is a Lisp, with all the power it entails. On the other, the development toolchain can be byzantine. With the advent of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.2ality.com/2015/06/web-assembly.html&#34;&gt;WebAssembly&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lukehoban/es6features/blob/master/README.md&#34;&gt;ECMAScript6&lt;/a&gt;, I have hopes of seeing tail call optimization (allowing true recursion) handled in ClojureScript, if not Clojure itself. And &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/reagent-project/reagent&#34;&gt;Reagent&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bhauman/lein-figwheel&#34;&gt;figwheel&lt;/a&gt; can make web development (not my strong suite) much easier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>River5 on Windows</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/02/22/river5-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/02/22/river5-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you know, I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dave_Winer&#34;&gt;Dave Winer&lt;/a&gt; and his &lt;a href=&#34;http://scripting.com/2014/06/02/whatIsARiverOfNewsAggregator.html&#34;&gt;River of News&lt;/a&gt; aggregators. His recent &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/scripting/river5&#34;&gt;River5&lt;/a&gt; is particularly nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: 17 Mar 2018. Although these notes discuss setting up River5 on a virtual server, I have used these instructions to set it up on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.org/products/raspberry-pi-3-model-b/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi 3 Model B&lt;/a&gt; sitting on my desk. It has been running for months without issue. In fact, it&amp;rsquo;s more reliable than my CloudAtCost rented server ever was.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve already &lt;a href=&#34;https://clartaq.github.io/yo-dave/2016/02/12/2016-02-12-cloudatcost-setup-notes/&#34;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; about installing on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://cloudatcost.com/&#34;&gt;CloudAtCost&lt;/a&gt; server running &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntu.com/&#34;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;. But it seems some folks are running into difficulty installing on Windows. It&amp;rsquo;s easy and works like a dream. Here&amp;rsquo;s how.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>River5 on Ubuntu 14.04 LTS with a CloudAtCost VS</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/02/14/river5-on-ubuntu-14.04-lts-with-a-cloudatcost-vs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/02/14/river5-on-ubuntu-14.04-lts-with-a-cloudatcost-vs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/scripting/river5&#34;&gt;River5&lt;/a&gt; is the latest in a series of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS&#34;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; News Aggretators written by &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dave_Winer&#34;&gt;Dave Winer&lt;/a&gt;. You can read his announcement &lt;a href=&#34;http://scripting.com/liveblog/users/davewiner/2016/02/09/0995.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. These notes describe how to set up a River of News on a Virtual Server (VS) purchased or rented from &lt;a href=&#34;http://cloudatcost.com/&#34;&gt;CloudAtCost&lt;/a&gt; and freshly imaged with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntu.com/&#34;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; 14.04.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These notes assume that you have done some work in configuring your VS with a user, other than root, that has super user privileges. If you need help doing the initial setup of your VS, look &lt;a href=&#34;https://clartaq.github.io/yo-dave/2016/02/12/2016-02-12-cloudatcost-setup-notes/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CloudAtCost Setup Notes</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/02/12/cloudatcost-setup-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/02/12/cloudatcost-setup-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;update-10-aug-2016&#34;&gt;Update: 10 Aug 2016&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a new and improved version of this post &lt;a href=&#34;https://yo-dave.com/2016/08/10/my-server-setup-process/&#34;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;. Look at that instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting with servers from &lt;a href=&#34;http://cloudatcost.com/&#34;&gt;CloudAtCost&lt;/a&gt;. As such, I tear them down and re-image them fairly frequently. These are my notes on how I do initial setup of servers that have been freshly imaged with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntu.com/&#34;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; 14.04 LTS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java JDK Install Fails on Windows 10</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/01/30/java-jdk-install-fails-on-windows-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/01/30/java-jdk-install-fails-on-windows-10/</guid>
      <description>An update to the Java JDK is always a good thing. I look forward to seeing all the new stuff. But my recent attempt to update to 1.8.0_72 only partially succeeded. I attempted to install the new updates, both update 71 and 72, and both failed to finish installing the JRE. The rest of the JDK seemed to install correctly and I have been able to use it successfully, but the local JRE failed to install, returning error code 1603.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dropbox Can Break Windows 10 Start Menu</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/01/26/dropbox-can-break-windows-10-start-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/01/26/dropbox-can-break-windows-10-start-menu/</guid>
      <description>The first time I tried to install Windows 10, I had to revert to 7 because the Start Menu started producing Critical Errors.
Naturally, I searched the web for solutions. None worked, including the suggestions made by Microsoft about using a particular sequence of logins, checking system files for corruption, and creating a new user and transferring all my data to the new user account.
Eventually, I came across this link to a post of possible solutions containing the usual stuff, but someone also mentioned that their system started working correctly once they removed Dropbox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s Broken Today</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2015/12/30/whats-broken-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2015/12/30/whats-broken-today/</guid>
      <description>Like most days, I got up ready to tackle a bunch of problems and features on some of the software I work on. But, as is often the case, I was stymied by technical problems and got almost nothing done. The problems?
 None of the JetBrains IDEs that I use could open a working terminal window. For most work, these are my tools of choice for programming tasks. Without a terminal, I can get by, but it isn’t as convenient or fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Thing About Upgrading to Windows 10...</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2015/12/23/the-best-thing-about-upgrading-to-windows-10.../</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2015/12/23/the-best-thing-about-upgrading-to-windows-10.../</guid>
      <description>Is that it shuts up the continual nagging to upgrade to Windows 10.
I tried to upgrade earlier this year but it was a miserable failure. Buggy, slow, missing device drivers, nosy, nosy, nosy.
It was a bit improved this time. A Windows 10 version of the driver for my Fujitsu ScanSnap S1500 finally appeared, so I thought I would try it again. The upgrade process was pretty smooth and the new driver works just fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Local Java JARS in Clojure Projects</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2015/10/03/using-local-java-jars-in-clojure-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2015/10/03/using-local-java-jars-in-clojure-projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sudoku&#34;&gt;Sudoku&lt;/a&gt; game program. Part of the program provides a user with the ability to generate new puzzles of a particular difficulty. Generating a puzzle usually requires two puzzle solvers: one that solves puzzles (slowly) like a human would, the other that solves puzzles (very quickly) like a computer would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than write my own from scratch, for this part of the development, I wanted to use an existing implementation of the machine-like solver. After a little research (more on this some other time), I found one I liked a lot &amp;ndash; the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/attractivechaos/plb/tree/master/sudoku&#34;&gt;Kudoku solver written in Java&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://attractivechaos.wordpress.com/2011/06/19/an-incomplete-review-of-sudoku-solver-implementations/&#34;&gt;attractive chaos&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how does one use a local jar file in a Clojure Project? Read on&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Windows 10 Update Experience</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2015/08/29/my-windows-10-update-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2015/08/29/my-windows-10-update-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just like millions of others, I tried the free upgrade to Windows 10. I waited a few weeks after it was available before trying it, just to see what the early fallout was before committing myself. It was pretty much a disaster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my system it was&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Too buggy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Too slow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Too nosy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Mono-Spaced Fonts in JavaFX</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2015/07/27/finding-mono-spaced-fonts-in-javafx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2015/07/27/finding-mono-spaced-fonts-in-javafx/</guid>
      <description>There are many use cases where a mono-spaced (fixed-width) font is useful in programming. Programming editors and creating program listings come to mind. But there doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be a consistent way of obtaining a list of all of the mono-spaced fonts installed in the operating system.
Back in the days of Swing, you usually had to grab a list of font families (e.g. Arial, Times New Roman, etc.) from AWT and then create a BufferedImage to print the font to and check layout widths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tasks and UI Updates in JavaFX</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2015/06/30/tasks-and-ui-updates-in-javafx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2015/06/30/tasks-and-ui-updates-in-javafx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I answered a &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/30980138/javafx-indeterminate-progress-bar-while-doing-a-process/30986188#30986188&#34;&gt;question&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/&#34;&gt;StackOverflow&lt;/a&gt; related to executing a long-running task in the background of a JavaFX application while updating the UI on the progress of that task. I have found myself coming back to that solution several times now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web vs. Native App Redux</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2015/05/28/web-vs.-native-app-redux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2015/05/28/web-vs.-native-app-redux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have been following along for awhile, you may have noted how conflicted I am about writing web apps &lt;em&gt;vs&lt;/em&gt;. native apps. I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking into &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meteor.com/&#34;&gt;Meteor&lt;/a&gt;, which makes the decision even thornier for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No More Disqus</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2015/05/15/no-more-disqus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 17:09:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2015/05/15/no-more-disqus/</guid>
      <description>Man, I am so fed up with companies that insist on tracking me. Disqus has a great commenting system. Great features. Widely used.
But they track you, building a pretty detailed profile, which they sell. They do it me and you if you comment on this site. Without telling either of us. So, Disqus is out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turning Off Disqus</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2015/05/15/turning-off-disqus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2015/05/15/turning-off-disqus/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been using Disqus to take care of the comments on this site. As of today, that is over.
The reason is simple. Tracking. They plan to build very detailed user profiles based on the comments that people leave around the net. I didn’t know, but they were spying on the people who comment on my stuff. Without telling anyone.
That’s over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ssh Cleverness</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2015/05/12/ssh-cleverness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2015/05/12/ssh-cleverness/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick note about using SSH. Recently I had to wipe and re-install Ubuntu. (More on that later.) That meant my ssh private key was wiped as well. In order to replace it, I copied the file from a Windows machine onto my newly installed Linux partition.
When I tried to log into some of my other servers, ssh gave me a warning about lax permissions and refused to log in without my password.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Drink Coffee Because it Tastes Good</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2015/05/10/i-drink-coffee-because-it-tastes-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2015/05/10/i-drink-coffee-because-it-tastes-good/</guid>
      <description>Seems like there have been a lot of posts recently about folks using coffee to optimize their energy or alertness levels. That’s just trying to use coffee as some sort of mind-altering drug. That’s wrong. You should drink coffee because you think it tastes good. That’s why I drink it.
How I Got Here Like most people, I was introduced to coffee by my parents. They drank it and I watched.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How this Blog Disappeared (and Reappeared) Again</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2015/05/06/how-this-blog-disappeared-and-reappeared-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2015/05/06/how-this-blog-disappeared-and-reappeared-again/</guid>
      <description>Some of you may have noticed that this blog disappeared again for awhile. It was on purpose this time.
As I noted in an earlier post, getting WordPress to work on this host has been a bit of a chore. I got tired of doing updates and installs of plugins and such manually. It was not particularly hard, just tiresome.
And then some warnings about particularly nasty XSS bugs appeared. At that time, I took the blog offline until I had some time to deal with things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focus Behavior Change between JavaFX 2 and JavaFX 8 when Selecting Rows in a TableView</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2015/04/18/focus-behavior-change-between-javafx-2-and-javafx-8-when-selecting-rows-in-a-tableview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2015/04/18/focus-behavior-change-between-javafx-2-and-javafx-8-when-selecting-rows-in-a-tableview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a little while now, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on an application that manages a list of documents, providing multiple views that the user can edit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://yo-dave.com/static/img/2015_04_18_Main_Screen_Capture_Cropped.PNG&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://yo-dave.com/static/img/2015_04_18_Main_Screen_Capture.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Image of the document manager main screen&#34; title=&#34;The document manager main screen&#34; /&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;small&gt;The document manager main screen&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user selects the document they wish to view or edit by selecting it from the large &lt;code&gt;TableView&lt;/code&gt; in the middle of the window. The area on the right provides controls to view and edit details. (The area on the left is for filtering the documents displayed in the central table.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on some early advice, I had watchers on the focus property of the fields that could be edited. When a control lost focus, any changes were written to the database. The user didn&amp;rsquo;t have to do anything to save their work. It just happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This worked with Java 7 and JavaFX 2. After the switch to Java 8 and JavaFX 8, things were not quite the same. If a user was making a change somewhere and then selected another document without moving to another editing view, the data was lost. The focus change notification did not arrive before the new document was selected in the table (repopulating the editing control before the data was saved.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overwhelming Java&#39;s Swing</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2015/01/06/overwhelming-javas-swing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 09:47:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2015/01/06/overwhelming-javas-swing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An odd thing happened recently. I have been working on a simulation that produces graphical and text updates as it progresses. That involves drawing a picture of the system and updating some textual elements of the user interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things seemed to work fine when the simulation was run with &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; inputs. However, when supplied with a set of parameters to produce a much simpler simulation, the user interface essentially locked up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Editor Productivity</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2014/12/21/editor-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2014/12/21/editor-productivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been away awhile, working on a new project. It&amp;rsquo;s part of an educational effort about molecular dynamics simulation. Although I&amp;rsquo;ve been working a lot with Clojure using emacs for editing, this project required a return to Java. As a result, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using NetBeans again. The difference in productivity was amazing and not in the way I expected.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OS Updates</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2014/10/16/os-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 13:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2014/10/16/os-updates/</guid>
      <description>I’ll admit it — I’m afraid of updates to the operating system. I fear them on Linux. I loathe them on Windows. iOS messes with basic behavior like battery life and network access. I don’t use OS X at the moment, so won’t comment on it here.
I am currently using Window 7 Pro, 64-bit. It’s been a few months since an update has bitten me, but that hasn’t always been the case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2014/10/16/wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 08:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2014/10/16/wordpress/</guid>
      <description>Now, I love WordPress. It’s easy to use and easy to administer. Except when it isn’t.
I run multiple sites on multiple servers. For the most part, they are trouble free. Except one site. This site. (Update 16 Aug 2017: This was referring to my site on CloudAtCost.)
You see, I can’t seem to load plugins or new themes or updates for some reason.
I run the same OS (Ubuntu 14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How This Blog Disappeared</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2014/10/14/how-this-blog-disappeared/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 08:03:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2014/10/14/how-this-blog-disappeared/</guid>
      <description>A few days, and a few posts, after setting up this blog, it disappeared. All I did was a distribution update on the system being used as the web server — Ubuntu 12.04 to 14.04.
The upgrade appeared to go well. Everything worked as I tested the newly upgraded system — except my blog directory was gone. No explanation. Nothing in the logs. Gone. My domains were pointing to empty space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging for Twenty Years</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2014/10/14/blogging-for-twenty-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 08:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2014/10/14/blogging-for-twenty-years/</guid>
      <description>For a change, this is not a rant; this is an homage.
Twenty years ago last week, Dave Winer started what later came to be called blogging. Dave’s remembrance of the event kind of rambles a bit, but that is his right. That’s what he gave us. Everyone now has the ability to say whatever they want and be read by whomever is interested. At a time when it seems that oppression of many sorts is winning, blogs are a strong statement of freedom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is My Hosting Service a Scam</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2014/10/14/is-my-hosting-service-a-scam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 08:01:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2014/10/14/is-my-hosting-service-a-scam/</guid>
      <description>As this is written, this blog is hosted on a server I bought from CloudAtCost. (Update 16 Aug 2017 This site is no longer hosted there.) This site sells or rents cloud servers for very low prices. As you might guess, a lot of people have jumped on, including many people (like myself) who just wanted to experiment with their own server for such a low cost.
With such a high number of newbies, there was a lot of need for support, as you would expect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About this Blog</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2014/10/13/about-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2014/10/13/about-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>(Note: This is the introductory post to a blog that was merged into this one. The original no longer exists.)
Hi.
Welcome to my new blog.
This is just a place for me to vent about problems with technology. Despite the name of the blog, I’m a technologist myself. I’ve spent decades developing medical technology. It’s likely that every reader in the States (and probably beyond) has been touched by technology I have worked on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to Web Apps (or not)</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2014/07/16/moving-to-web-apps-or-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2014/07/16/moving-to-web-apps-or-not/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a desktop kind of guy. I prefer desktop PCs, desktop programs, desktop programming. But I am also a cross-platform guy. Hence my interest in Java, and by extension, Clojure. But I would like those things to run on my tablet and (other people&amp;rsquo;s) phone. Doing that with Java seems to be more work than it is worth.
Hence, I&amp;rsquo;ve been considering web apps as a possible future direction. (Seems everyone else has figured this out already.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Theme</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2014/04/30/a-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 09:59:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2014/04/30/a-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>This probably has no interest to anyone but me, but you may notice a change in the blog theme today. I&amp;rsquo;ve been dissatisfied with the typography of the blog for quite some time. Today I set out to try to find a theme that had better typography. Man, what a mess!
There are a zillion WordPress themes out there. Some awful, but many quite good. However, finding a minimalist theme intended for writing and reading is surprisingly difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which Version of Java will Leiningen Run from an Emacs Shell</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2014/04/21/which-version-of-java-will-leiningen-run-from-an-emacs-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 13:51:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2014/04/21/which-version-of-java-will-leiningen-run-from-an-emacs-shell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been updating some of my projects to use the newly released Java 8. That includes many Clojure projects. These are just &amp;ldquo;flow of consciousness&amp;rdquo; debugging notes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating to Java 8 and NetBeans 8 on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2014/03/30/updating-to-java-8-and-netbeans-8-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 13:42:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2014/03/30/updating-to-java-8-and-netbeans-8-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just some notes on how I updated to the recent releases of Java 8 and NetBeans 8 on Ubuntu 13.10 (64 bit) running the Xfce desktop environment (Xubuntu).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Something New. Comments!</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2014/03/26/something-new.-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 13:33:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2014/03/26/something-new.-comments/</guid>
      <description>Well, it&amp;rsquo;s been a long time coming and I&amp;rsquo;m still a little unsure about it, but starting now, this site will allow comments. I&amp;rsquo;ve explained why I didn&amp;rsquo;t allow them before, but I&amp;rsquo;m adding Disqus-powered discussions to the blog. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how that goes.
If everything that comes in is just spam, I&amp;rsquo;ll disable comments again. If comments are useful, civil and on topic, they will remain.
And we&amp;rsquo;ll see if anyone thinks any of this stuff is interesting enough to comment on in the first place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Program I&#39;d Like to Find or Write</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2014/03/04/another-program-id-like-to-find-or-write/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 13:26:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2014/03/04/another-program-id-like-to-find-or-write/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned before, I use several cloud storage services. However, being a cheap bastard, I have only signed up for free accounts up to now. That means I have lots of little bits of storage scattered here and there (although recently Box gave me 50GB free and my Copy account has risen to 25GB). But that means having to keep track of where I put certain things. It sure would be nice to have a program that would aggregate all these little pieces into a single thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saving and Restoring Program Configuration across Sessions in Clojure</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2014/01/06/saving-and-restoring-program-configuration-across-sessions-in-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 13:13:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2014/01/06/saving-and-restoring-program-configuration-across-sessions-in-clojure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like to use programs that can remember what I was doing the last time I was working with them. They should restore the window just as I had it, remember which file(s) I was working with, what preferences I had selected, and so on. Naturally, I want the programs I write to be just as considerate of the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some time, I&amp;rsquo;ve been fretting over the best way to do this in a Clojure program. Should I provide wrappers around the Java Preferences API? Some other mechanism? Turns out I should just embrace simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaFX Still Not Ready?</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2013/12/29/javafx-still-not-ready/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2013/12/29/javafx-still-not-ready/</guid>
      <description>Just a short rant about JavaFX because I&amp;rsquo;m pissed about it at the moment. I enjoy using it for the most part but it sometimes throws up surprising obstacles in otherwise routine work. The latest for me was an unexpected lack of a spinner control. There are alternatives in some open source projects, but, really? No spinners built in?
This is almost as gob-smacking weird as the lack of dialogs. (Ok, there are some dialogs, like for opening/saving files, but not much in the way of user-programmable dialogs built in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More on Loading Fonts</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2013/08/12/more-on-loading-fonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2013/08/12/more-on-loading-fonts/</guid>
      <description>A couple days ago, I posted a little snippet showing how to load and font from a list of preferred fonts using Clojure and JavaFX. Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve extended the demo a bit to show how to load both fonts installed on the OS and fonts from a resource file.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the new snippet.
(ns clojure_font_loading.core (:gen-class :extends javafx.application.Application) (:import [javafx.application Application] [javafx.event EventHandler] [javafx.scene Scene] [avafx.scene.control Button] [javafx.scene.layout StackPane VBox] [javafx.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loading Fonts Like CSS</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2013/08/10/loading-fonts-like-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2013/08/10/loading-fonts-like-css/</guid>
      <description>Just wanted to pass along a little snippet I have found myself using fairly frequently. CSS has the ability to specify the appropriate font to use in displaying a document. It handles the tag in such a way that it can gracefully degrade from a &amp;ldquo;preferred&amp;rdquo; font through a series of less ideal typefaces depending on what&amp;rsquo;s available on the machine doing the display.
That&amp;rsquo;s a handy facility to have, even on Windows, which can have different fonts available depending on the version of Windows and what software has been installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paths with Spaces, I Give Up</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2013/08/08/paths-with-spaces-i-give-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2013/08/08/paths-with-spaces-i-give-up/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to look into the Pedestal framework for creating web-based applications in Clojure. However, one of the requirements is Leiningen 2.2.0 or greater. And, as I&amp;rsquo;ve written before, version 2.2 will not install on my system because of spaces in the path of the user home directory. (&amp;rdquo;C:\Users\David Clark&amp;rdquo; on my system.)
My user profile name is &amp;ldquo;david&amp;rdquo;. That&amp;rsquo;s what I use to sign on with. The fact that my home directory uses &amp;ldquo;David Clark&amp;rdquo; is an unfortunate result of how the computer was set up at the factory when I custom ordered it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N-Queens</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2013/08/06/n-queens/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2013/08/06/n-queens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eight_queens_puzzle&#34;&gt;N-Queens&lt;/a&gt; puzzle is a classic computer science problem. In fact, it&amp;rsquo;s much older than discipline of computer science. It is usually used as a problem to introduce students to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Backtracking&#34;&gt;backtracking algorithms&lt;/a&gt; in computer science. I was first introduced to the problem in Niklaus Wirth&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0130224189&#34;&gt;Algorithms + Data Structures = Programs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; back in the &amp;lsquo;70s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought it might be interesting to write an updated version in my continuing effort to become proficient in &lt;a href=&#34;http://clojure.org/&#34;&gt;Clojure&lt;/a&gt;.  My intent was to write a simple working version, then use the concurrency features of the language to write a parallel version and see what kind of performance gain was possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Storage at Copy</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2013/08/03/cloud-storage-at-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2013 17:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2013/08/03/cloud-storage-at-copy/</guid>
      <description>Update Copy was discontinued on 1 May 2016.
I use the Cloud very simply, nothing elaborate. I use BitBucket (Now I use HelixTeamHub cloud.) to keep track of my repositories. I use DropBox to store copies of scientific publications and Fargo outlines. For important stuff, I use SpiderOak because of its great security model. I think I have an iCloud account somewhere. That&amp;rsquo;s it.
This morning, I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with a new service called Copy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java-Clojure Interop: An Update</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2013/06/25/java-clojure-interop-an-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 18:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2013/06/25/java-clojure-interop-an-update/</guid>
      <description>My most popular answer on Stack Overflow has to do with Clojure-Java interop. Since that answer was written, some of the tools used in the answer, specifically enclojure (Broken Link), have been deprecated. Because many of the follow-up questions related to how to build a working version of the answer, I thought it might be a good idea to update the post with modern tools.
As this is written, the tools used include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Default JavaFX Platform in NetBeans</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2013/06/19/default-javafx-platform-in-netbeans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 16:26:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2013/06/19/default-javafx-platform-in-netbeans/</guid>
      <description>Update: With Java 8, the JavaFX library is included in the JDK. The machinations described here are no longer necessary.
Every time I update the default JDK used by NetBeans, I also want to update the default JavaFX platform. And I always forget how. Looking on the web usually results in finding methods that just don&amp;rsquo;t work. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I do it.
 In NetBeans (7.3 as of this writing), select the &amp;ldquo;Tools&amp;rdquo; menu and the &amp;ldquo;Java Platforms&amp;rdquo; drop-down menu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keyboard Shortcuts for JavaFX Buttons</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2013/06/04/keyboard-shortcuts-for-javafx-buttons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 04:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2013/06/04/keyboard-shortcuts-for-javafx-buttons/</guid>
      <description>Most programs written for graphical user interfaces still provide a way to operate with the keyboard, requiring minimal mouse usage. The thought is that expert users will want to speed through their work keeping their fingers on the keyboard rather than devote an entire hands worth of fingers to controlling the mouse. I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning JavaFX, the eventual replacement for the Swing UI framework on Java, and wanted to explore how shortcut functionality had changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaFX KeyCodeCombinations in Clojure</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2013/06/01/javafx-keycodecombinations-in-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 22:26:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2013/06/01/javafx-keycodecombinations-in-clojure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting with adding keyboard accelerators to some of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://clojure.org/&#34;&gt;Clojure&lt;/a&gt; programs I&amp;rsquo;ve written with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javafx/overview/index.html&#34;&gt;JavaFX&lt;/a&gt;-based user interfaces. As part of that investigation, I tried to translate the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Java_%28programming_language%29&#34;&gt;Java &lt;/a&gt; program &lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.example8.com/category/view/id/76&#34; title=&#34;Link to Java version of program.&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;Broken Link&lt;/strong&gt;) to Clojure. The program just puts up a window with a menu bar containing only a &amp;ldquo;&lt;code&gt;File&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rdquo; menu which itself contains one item, &amp;ldquo;&lt;code&gt;Exit&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rdquo;. Most programs provide a keyboard shortcut or accelerator to close the program with a &lt;code&gt;Ctrl-X&lt;/code&gt; (on Windows). Figuring out how to add that functionality was a bit of an issue for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Clojure Development Toolchain</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2013/05/21/the-clojure-development-toolchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 21:58:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2013/05/21/the-clojure-development-toolchain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things about &lt;a href=&#34;http://clojure.org/&#34;&gt;Clojure&lt;/a&gt; that is difficult for beginners is the process of creating and running programs. I would argue that it is more difficult than learning the language itself. There is no &amp;ldquo;one-button&amp;rdquo; provisioning system that would set up some sort of canonical development environment. This long post will talk about setting up Leiningen and Emacs to make a comfortable environment for developing in Clojure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clojure, JavaFX and Tic-Tac-Toe</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2013/05/08/clojure-javafx-and-tic-tac-toe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 17:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2013/05/08/clojure-javafx-and-tic-tac-toe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I have been experimenting with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javafx/overview/index.html&#34; title=&#34;Link to JavaFX developer&#34;&gt;JavaFX&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;http://clojure.org/&#34; title=&#34;Link to the Clojure language home page.&#34;&gt;Clojure&lt;/a&gt;. Initially, in one of my experiments, I wanted to learn how to re-size a game-board interface as it&amp;rsquo;s containing window was re-sized. In the past I&amp;rsquo;ve had medical device interfaces that draw a representation of a physical device and these drawings must re-size as their window is re-sized. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://clartaq.github.io/yo-dave/2013/02/18/2013-02-18-re-sizing-an-interface-in-javafx-and-clojure/&#34;&gt;initial experiment&lt;/a&gt; was with a simple interface for Tic-Tac-Toe. Since I had such a nice interface, I thought, why not program the complete game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Styled Dialogs in JavaFX with JFXtras MonologFX</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2013/05/08/styled-dialogs-in-javafx-with-jfxtras-monologfx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 14:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2013/05/08/styled-dialogs-in-javafx-with-jfxtras-monologfx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been having a lot of fun learning &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/overview/javafx-overview-2158620.html&#34; title=&#34;Link to JavaFX developer&#34;&gt;JavaFX&lt;/a&gt;, even after many years of using the Java Swing framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing about JavaFX that I still don&amp;rsquo;t understand is the lack of built-in support for dialogs. Well, that shortcoming has annoyed enough people that there are several efforts underway to provide dialog functionality. One of those is part of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://jfxtras.org/&#34; title=&#34;Link to the JFXtras home page.&#34;&gt;JFXtras&lt;/a&gt; project, &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.oracle.com/javajungle/entry/monologfx_floss_javafx_dialogs_for&#34; title=&#34;Link to MonologFX introduction blog.&#34;&gt;MonologFX&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re-sizing an Interface in JavaFX and Clojure</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2013/02/18/re-sizing-an-interface-in-javafx-and-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 21:48:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2013/02/18/re-sizing-an-interface-in-javafx-and-clojure/</guid>
      <description>Since JavaFX is the future of the user interface for Java, I&amp;rsquo;ve started trying to learn it. Since I&amp;rsquo;m also learning Clojure, I&amp;rsquo;m doing the work in that language.
One of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking into is how the interface responds to resizing. If you have all of your controls in a nice layout, that is usually taken care of for you. But how do you handle things if the interface is not made up of standard components, something like a graphical game interface for example?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to a Real Keyboard</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2013/01/24/back-to-a-real-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 22:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2013/01/24/back-to-a-real-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>As some of you know, we&amp;rsquo;ve spent the last several months moving around looking for a nice place to settle down. That&amp;rsquo;s finished. We&amp;rsquo;re now in Salem, Virginia.
Before starting that search, we bought a laptop to take over the duties of the desktop. On the night before we left Tucson, I dumped a cup of water on it and fried the keyboard and other parts. It turns out the model was too new to get replacement parts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Interview Questions</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2012/03/29/developer-interview-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2012 08:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2012/03/29/developer-interview-questions/</guid>
      <description>Picking the right people to expand an organization is one of the most important things you can do. In my career, I&amp;rsquo;ve participated in many, many interviews on both sides of the desk. As a scientist and manager, my interviews have been very different from those being proposed for hiring developers. From that perspective, there seem to be two categories of questions that are popular right now that seem to be pointless, potentially embarrassing, or outright business risks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2012 - The Year We All Unplug?</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2012/01/04/2012-the-year-we-all-unplug/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 18:02:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2012/01/04/2012-the-year-we-all-unplug/</guid>
      <description>Well, Happy New Year everyone.
It seems like I&amp;rsquo;ve been hearing a lot of buzz about getting unconnected. Everything from hotels offering special deals on stays where you are forced to turn off (or turn in) all your gizmos, to advice to disconnect to improve your productivity. Could it be that the pendulum has started to swing in the other direction?
Sit back and enjoy the quiet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Favorite Programming Books</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/12/01/favorite-programming-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 11:16:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/12/01/favorite-programming-books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every programmer seems to have their own list of favorite programming books. The lists are very personal and seem to be influenced by the age of the programmer, their training, and their field of endeavor. My own list follows.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Programming: A Paradox?</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/12/01/functional-programming-a-paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 09:25:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/12/01/functional-programming-a-paradox/</guid>
      <description>I like the idea of Functional Programming. It just appeals to my own mathematical bent I think. A few of the central tenets include immutability of data and creating functions that always produce the same results given the same arguments by avoiding side effects. All this to minimize generation of unpredictable results (errors). But wait a minute. There is another field of study with a long and deep history of research, random number generation, that says it is virtually impossible to generate truly random (unpredictable) results on a computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter: A Lack of Communication</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/12/01/twitter-a-lack-of-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 08:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/12/01/twitter-a-lack-of-communication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a rant that I just have to get off my chest.Twitter just doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide any meaningful communication and I can&amp;rsquo;t understand the appeal. Imagine a newspaper consisting of just the headlines or a magazine containing only the article titles &amp;ndash; that is essentially Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wilcoxon Matched Pairs</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/11/14/wilcoxon-matched-pairs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2011 18:32:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/11/14/wilcoxon-matched-pairs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At my previous employer, our goal was to stain tissue samples such that a pathologist could examine them microscopically and easily make unambiguous diagnoses of disease state. Experiments typically involved getting subjective judgments from pathologists about which samples were &amp;ldquo;better&amp;rdquo; in some way. How do you do statistics on those type of results?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unconnected</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/10/27/unconnected/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2011 21:48:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/10/27/unconnected/</guid>
      <description>My wife and I just returned from a long cruise to Hawaii and back. During that time, we were just about completely disconnected from the mobile world &amp;ndash; no access to email, cell phone, fax. There was sporadic television available.
On balance I didn&amp;rsquo;t miss it too much. I continued to work on problems in my head, looking forward to the chance to get back to work on them when we returned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Data Grid Component -- A Personal Failing</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/09/22/java-data-grid-component-a-personal-failing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2011 08:06:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/09/22/java-data-grid-component-a-personal-failing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many of the programs I write need a way to enter and edit a two-dimensional grid of data in the user interface. Such a grid doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to be a full-fledged spreadsheet, just provide flexible data entry and editing. Alas, there doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be such a thing and I haven&amp;rsquo;t created one that I&amp;rsquo;m satisfied with.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spare Time Projects, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/09/17/spare-time-projects-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2011 00:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/09/17/spare-time-projects-part-2/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago, I wrote a post about &amp;ldquo;spare time&amp;rdquo; projects &amp;ndash; programming projects undertaken to learn something new, try something out, see how something works. These are activities undertaken to improve your skills and, maybe, scratch an itch that&amp;rsquo;s been bothering you. These projects aren&amp;rsquo;t typically related to work.
In the past few days, Oren Eini (aka Ayende Rahien) wrote a couple of posts expressing the opinion that if you don&amp;rsquo;t do such projects, he probably doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to hire you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Praise of the Self-Taught Programmer</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/09/16/in-praise-of-the-self-taught-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 01:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/09/16/in-praise-of-the-self-taught-programmer/</guid>
      <description>Programming is one of the few professions where you regularly see self-taught practitioners. They have little or no formal education in the subject, but they often do quite well. In some cases, I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with some who were considered outstanding in their area of focus, like machine control or real-time.
Granted, early in their careers, these folks often produce nasty messes that happen to work well enough but are simply not maintainable or not extendable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Color Deconvolution</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/09/14/color-deconvolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 20:04:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/09/14/color-deconvolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One method I&amp;rsquo;ve used in a number of imaging tasks is Color Deconvolution. You can think of color deconvolution as figuring out how much of each of a group of colors contributes to the final color of the pixels in an image.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write the Manual First</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/08/22/write-the-manual-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 16:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/08/22/write-the-manual-first/</guid>
      <description>Back when I was involved in designing medical devices, I had a saying to help guide the design: &amp;ldquo;Write the manual first.&amp;rdquo; This seemed to be an easier way for the teams to clearly describe what the device should do. Once everyone had a good feeling for how the system should operate, it was easier to move on to the more formal requirements management. Surprisingly, not everyone on the team was as fascinated with that as the Systems Integration team ;-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s Cross-Platform Now?</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/08/22/whats-cross-platform-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 10:13:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/08/22/whats-cross-platform-now/</guid>
      <description>It used to be that &amp;ldquo;cross-platform&amp;rdquo; meant making a program that could be run on Windows, Macs, and Linux PCs. To create a program that worked on all three platforms, you could write it in Java, or maybe Python or C depending on what the program needed to do. That&amp;rsquo;s not really the case anymore.
First there were smart-phones. In that case you could still fall back on Java ME for some phones, but not all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Programmers</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/08/13/old-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2011 10:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/08/13/old-programmers/</guid>
      <description>Seems like I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading a lot of conversation about when you become too old to be a good programmer. I&amp;rsquo;ve even seen someone ask, with apparent sincerity, if 26 was too old. Of course anyone with any sense realizes that the answer is &amp;ldquo;Never!&amp;rdquo; As I&amp;rsquo;ve watched how my own performance has changed over the years, there have been a few obvious changes.
 I am way less likely to chase after the &amp;ldquo;shiny new thing&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Process versus Experience</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/07/15/process-versus-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 23:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/07/15/process-versus-experience/</guid>
      <description>Today I came across a blog that describes a sentiment that comes up periodically. It describes a development group that does not believe it needs to follow the agile development process. The team is composed of experienced developers with a track record of delivering the goods.
I&amp;rsquo;m not much of a fan of agile myself, but I believe in process as part of software development. I think the real sentiment being expressed is that experience trumps process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sign Test</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/07/09/the-sign-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2011 22:37:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/07/09/the-sign-test/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes weakness is a strength. That certainly seems to be the case for the lowly sign test. It is about the simplest statistical significance test imaginable. But if it tells you something is important, it probably is.
Usually when you hear people talk about the &amp;ldquo;power&amp;rdquo; of a statistical test, they are referring to the ability of the test to detect a significant difference when one exists. For example, Student&amp;rsquo;s t test is a favorite and very powerful test for differences in means when you have data meeting the underlying assumptions of the test.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spare Time Projects</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/06/27/spare-time-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/06/27/spare-time-projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s pretty common to see discussions about how to determine if a candidate for a programming job has a &amp;ldquo;passion&amp;rdquo; for programming and software. One of the usual pieces of advice is to ask about the projects someone does in their &amp;ldquo;spare time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Away! It Isn&#39;t Perfect Yet!</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/06/26/go-away-it-isnt-perfect-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 23:28:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/06/26/go-away-it-isnt-perfect-yet/</guid>
      <description>Not a very inviting byline, I admit. People have asked what it means. It&amp;rsquo;s a joke of course.
It&amp;rsquo;s a constant reminder not to fall prey to something I&amp;rsquo;ve seen block people from getting things done and out there time and time again. People (myself included) are afraid to put something in front of their peers or the public because it isn&amp;rsquo;t quite perfect yet. There&amp;rsquo;s just a little more fiddling needed to get it just right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things to Remember when Updating Java Version</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/06/17/things-to-remember-when-updating-java-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2011 14:27:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/06/17/things-to-remember-when-updating-java-version/</guid>
      <description>New versions of Java come out fairly frequently. On my system, I need to remember to update other settings to use the updates. These include:
 The JAVA_HOME environment variable The path to the bin directory in the PATH environment variable The &amp;ldquo;Program Files\Netbeans x.x\etc\netbeans.conf&amp;rdquo; file (on Windows) These settings keep everything building and running correctly.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binomial Confidence Intervals -- BinomConf</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/06/14/binomial-confidence-intervals-binomconf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 16:57:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/06/14/binomial-confidence-intervals-binomconf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Way back in my career there was a need to calculate binomial confidence intervals on experiments with very large numbers of trials (thousands to tens of thousands.) The statistics packages of the time couldn&amp;rsquo;t seem to handle such large numbers of trials.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friendly Incompetence or Evil Conspiracy</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/06/12/friendly-incompetence-or-evil-conspiracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2011 01:50:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/06/12/friendly-incompetence-or-evil-conspiracy/</guid>
      <description>As regular readers know, there have been &amp;ldquo;issues&amp;rdquo; with my computer, a relatively new Falcon Northwest Talon. Their service representatives were never able to solve a relatively simple problem. Were they actually unable to do so or did they choose not to?
This computer has generally been excellent. But there have been issues with it regularly. I believe the first was precipitated by Microsoft Update and was not at all the fault of the computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu 11.04 Upgrade: Not So Excellent</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/05/15/ubuntu-11.04-upgrade-not-so-excellent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2011 17:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/05/15/ubuntu-11.04-upgrade-not-so-excellent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntu.com&#34; title=&#34;Link to Ubuntu Linux home page&#34;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linux.com&#34; title=&#34;Link to Linux home page&#34;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt; distribution came out with version 11.04 a few days ago. These upgrades very seldom go smoothly on my systems. This was not an exception.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elise&#39;s Rule</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/04/17/elises-rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2011 01:09:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/04/17/elises-rule/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Based on repeated observations, my wife, Elise, has formed a simple rule:
&amp;gt; When Dave has any extra time off, the computer will be broken &amp;ndash; big time.
It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;freaking uncanny&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me2 iPad2</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/04/09/me2-ipad2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2011 00:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/04/09/me2-ipad2/</guid>
      <description>My wife and I have birthdays that are just a few days apart. This year we ended up getting each other an iPad 2. We have an iMac but have never bought into the whole iPod, iPhone, iThis&amp;rsquo;nThat thing.
We were really excited to get started playing with our new toys. They came in nice boxes with the needed accessories, but little else including any guide on how to get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vacuum Cleaners - A Rant</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/04/03/vacuum-cleaners-a-rant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 20:07:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/04/03/vacuum-cleaners-a-rant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is really something unrelated to most of the content here, but I have to get something off my chest. You would think that after more than a century of engineering effort vacuums cleaners would be a solved problem. Sadly, that is not the case.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Theme Background Image</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/04/03/dark-theme-background-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2011 16:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/04/03/dark-theme-background-image/</guid>
      <description>As has been noted before, Arizona contains enough photogenic scenery that even I get a nice photo now and then. Here&amp;rsquo;s one that has been manipulated a bit into a nice abstract background for blogs or program windows.
This was taken at the Bryce-Thompson Arboretum in Florence Arizona in the Autumn of 2010. The photo originated as a snapshot of a rock covered with a bluish-gray lichen and a rather bright green moss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why No Comments?</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/03/18/why-no-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 17:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/03/18/why-no-comments/</guid>
      <description>There are two primary reasons that comments are not enabled on this site.
 These are just notes I write to myself. They don&amp;rsquo;t get much attention other than when I want to remind myself of something. It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be fair to solicit comments and then just ignore them. Comment spam. Related to the above, I just don&amp;rsquo;t check in often enough and would not effectively moderate and eliminate spam.  This does not mean that the site will never be opened up to comments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidying up the Ubuntu Grub2 Boot Menu</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/03/13/tidying-up-the-ubuntu-grub2-boot-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2011 01:27:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/03/13/tidying-up-the-ubuntu-grub2-boot-menu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My wife and I share a computer that dual boots Ubuntu Linux and Windows. Too, when we upgrade computers, I tend to take the hard drive(s) from the old computer to the new computer. The boot menus created by the grub2 program can be a bit confusing for the uninitiated. As kernel updates are added, the list gets longer. The old Windows drive appears in the list, as well as the recovery partitions that manufacturers often put on Windows drives. In the normal course of things the Windows menu items can get pushed out of view at the bottom of the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Where&amp;rsquo;s the Windows menu item!?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Which of all these Windows choices is the right one?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not a happy situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the interests of domestic harmony (and to assure that a Windows recovery partition is not booted inadvertently), a little clean up is required.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parsing Signed Numbers in ANTLR</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/03/08/parsing-signed-numbers-in-antlr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2011 15:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/03/08/parsing-signed-numbers-in-antlr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the more interesting things I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on lately is a scripting language to drive a simulation system. It describes nominal values of key parameters, how to vary them, do an analysis, gather the results and present those results. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.antlr.org/&#34; title=&#34;ANTLR Home Page&#34;&gt;ANTLR&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.antlr3.org/works/&#34; title=&#34;ANTLRWorks Home Page&#34;&gt;ANTLRWorks&lt;/a&gt; are usually great tools to create the lexer and parser of such a scripting language. That&amp;rsquo;s how I started out this time too. Since I thought it would be trivial, I left parsing signed numbers to nearly the end of the project. It was a bit of a surprise how difficult this was.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snow in Tucson</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/02/27/snow-in-tucson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2011 19:22:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/02/27/snow-in-tucson/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s pretty rare for photos to be included on this blog. But it&amp;rsquo;s even rarer to see snow here in Tucson. So here are a few pics of what we woke up to this morning.
Snow-Covered Palms at the Side of our House
Our palm trees are not really used to this!
If you&amp;rsquo;re a golf fan, you are probably aware that the Accenture Golf Tournament is being played here. This is a view over toward the town of Marana.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Lisp/Scheme/Clojure</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/02/25/getting-started-with-lisp/scheme/clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2011 16:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/02/25/getting-started-with-lisp/scheme/clojure/</guid>
      <description>Ya know, this point just keeps slapping me in the face. It seems that people don&amp;rsquo;t stop trying to use Lisp because they don&amp;rsquo;t like the language. A lot of people stop because they don&amp;rsquo;t like the programming environment. Looking around the Q&amp;amp;A sites there seem to be many more questions about setting up a programming environment for the Lisp family of languages than there are for the more mainstream languages like Java and C++.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unknown USB Device</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/02/22/unknown-usb-device/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 01:26:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/02/22/unknown-usb-device/</guid>
      <description>After my many re-installations of Windows 7, I often have an &amp;ldquo;Unknown Device&amp;rdquo; in the list of USB devices shown by the Windows Device Manager. It is almost always because of my LogiTech G110 keyboard. It works as a USB keyboard with no additional setup after these re-installations, but its extra functionality (like the cool lighted key caps) require that the device driver be installed. Doing so invariably removes the last &amp;ldquo;Unknown Device&amp;rdquo; warning from the device list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Update Trashed My Computer -- AGAIN!</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/02/22/windows-update-trashed-my-computer-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 00:23:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/02/22/windows-update-trashed-my-computer-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever since the purchase of a nice new system running Windows 7 Professional, I have been plagued by periodic system crashes. Crashes that make the system unstable and that finally make it unbootable. And it&amp;rsquo;s all the fault of Windows Update.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clojure and Java Interaction</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/02/13/clojure-and-java-interaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2011 02:10:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/02/13/clojure-and-java-interaction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my most-upvoted &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/2181774/calling-clojure-from-java/2187427#2187427&#34;&gt;answers&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/&#34;&gt;Stackoverflow&lt;/a&gt; is a simple example of how to call &lt;a href=&#34;http://clojure.org/&#34;&gt;Clojure&lt;/a&gt; functions from Java. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t require calling through the Clojure run-time as so many responses do. But there is more to writing programs than calling static functions, as in my answer. You also might need to call methods &lt;em&gt;of&lt;/em&gt; objects and &lt;em&gt;on&lt;/em&gt; objects across the Clojure/Java divide.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathematica and MATLAB</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/02/11/mathematica-and-matlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2011 01:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/02/11/mathematica-and-matlab/</guid>
      <description>In some ways there are many similarities between Mathematica® and MATLAB®. From the simplest point of view, both are computer mathematics systems. I use both at work and, thus, am a wizard at neither. Let me expose my biases up front though. I like Mathematica enough that I have paid actual money to have a copy at home. With that bias in mind, let&amp;rsquo;s look at some of the differences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Literate Programming</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/02/06/literate-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2011 01:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/02/06/literate-programming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever since &lt;a href=&#34;http://www-cs-faculty.stanford.edu/~uno/index.html&#34;&gt;Donald Knuth&lt;/a&gt; published &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.literateprogramming.com/knuthweb.pdf&#34;&gt;Literate Programming&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; back in 1984, I&amp;rsquo;ve been a fan. Telling a computer how to run a program and helping a human understand it are two different but very necessary things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light Theme Background Image</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/01/30/light-theme-background-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2011 01:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/01/30/light-theme-background-image/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Arizona, where I live, has a lot of very photogenic scenery. I am by no means a very talented photographer, but with all the opportunities around here, every once in a while, even I manage to snap a nice image.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syntax Highlighting</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/01/30/syntax-highlighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2011 01:11:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/01/30/syntax-highlighting/</guid>
      <description>Update 2017-08-19: This post refers to a time when the blog was hosted in WordPress. It isn&amp;rsquo;t really applicable anymore. But it may provide some guidance to someone who happens to come across it.
Since this blog is mostly about programming, there are a lot of code listings. To make those listings more easily readable, highlighting syntax in the listings is a good thing.
Of all of the syntax highlighters I have tried, the SyntaxHighlighter JavaScript tool by Alex Gorbachev is the one I most prefer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Closure in Clojure</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/01/29/a-closure-in-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 23:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/01/29/a-closure-in-clojure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back when closures were first explained to me, a long time ago, I thought &amp;ldquo;sounds like a language with pass-by-reference semantics like Pascal.&amp;rdquo; Of course, it isn&amp;rsquo;t quite that simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clojure has a lot of nice features that work naturally to give you a &amp;ldquo;better Java than Java&amp;rdquo;. Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of using a closure that is not at all easy in Java.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting enclojure 1.4 to work</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/01/27/getting-enclojure-1.4-to-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2011 01:31:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/01/27/getting-enclojure-1.4-to-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve used &lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.enclojure.org&#34;&gt;enclojure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;Broken Link&lt;/strong&gt;) for a long time (in internet years). It has always seemed a bit finicky. However, with the 1.4 release and the switch to using &lt;a href=&#34;http://maven.apache.org&#34;&gt;Maven&lt;/a&gt; as the build tool, things stopped working. Projects that had worked fine before no longer compiled or executed. The &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; section of the enclojure web page appears to be hopelessly out of date and actually misleading. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I had to do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideas for Simulated Evolution</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/01/25/ideas-for-simulated-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 00:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/01/25/ideas-for-simulated-evolution/</guid>
      <description>Note: This is a re-post of an earlier entry recovered from a different blogging system.
After entering and running the evolution.lisp example from Land of Lisp, I have some ideas for additional traits.
Here are a few.
 Size, Carnivorous Animals. Add a feature to allow the animals to be of different sizes. Larger animals would expend energy faster. When two animals occupy, the same cell, the larger would try to eat the smaller, taking it&amp;rsquo;s energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re-sizing an Icon in Java for Swing</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/01/23/re-sizing-an-icon-in-java-for-swing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2011 01:41:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/01/23/re-sizing-an-icon-in-java-for-swing/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you have a resource like an icon or image that almost works, but not quite. For example, there was a question on StackOverflow about how to re-size an existing icon to fit in the smaller location at the lower right corner of a JScrollPane. The original poster was close. Here&amp;rsquo;s the code I came up with that actually worked.
import javax.swing.*; import java.awt.*; public class CornerButton extends JFrame { public CornerButton() { JTextArea area = new JTextArea(20, 20); JScrollPane scroll = new JScrollPane(area); Icon icn = UIManager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving Old Posts</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/01/23/moving-old-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2011 00:56:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/01/23/moving-old-posts/</guid>
      <description>Since I&amp;rsquo;m going through the setup again, I thought I would start out with some older posts from other systems (the few that remain). Don&amp;rsquo;t pay much attention to the dates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So, Dr. Clark. We meet again!</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/01/22/so-dr.-clark.-we-meet-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 23:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/01/22/so-dr.-clark.-we-meet-again/</guid>
      <description>Well, here we are again. You, me, and WordPress. It seems like I go through this setup a lot. Over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried other blogging platforms, and even toyed with the idea of creating one of my own for fun like one of my heroes, Brian Carper (Broken Link). But I just keep coming back here. Why do I ever leave?
There are really a couple of reasons. I do this a lot because of hardware and backup failures.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>