<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>leiningen on Yo-Dave</title>
    <link>https://yo-dave.com/tags/leiningen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in leiningen on Yo-Dave</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2011-2020, David D. Clark. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 09:54:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yo-dave.com/tags/leiningen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Leiningen passing Invalid Flags to Java Compiler</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2017/05/14/leiningen-passing-invalid-flags-to-java-compiler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 09:54:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2017/05/14/leiningen-passing-invalid-flags-to-java-compiler/</guid>
      <description>Just a note about some weirdness in my work process and it’s solution.
A few weeks ago, I started noticing some weirdness in trying to use some tools with Leiningen while developing a program in Clojure. When running tools like kibit, lein would fail with an error from javac about an invalid flag. Initially these flags were for attempts to set the file encoding. And the file encoding kept changing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Local Java JARS in Clojure Projects</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2015/10/03/using-local-java-jars-in-clojure-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2015/10/03/using-local-java-jars-in-clojure-projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sudoku&#34;&gt;Sudoku&lt;/a&gt; game program. Part of the program provides a user with the ability to generate new puzzles of a particular difficulty. Generating a puzzle usually requires two puzzle solvers: one that solves puzzles (slowly) like a human would, the other that solves puzzles (very quickly) like a computer would.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than write my own from scratch, for this part of the development, I wanted to use an existing implementation of the machine-like solver. After a little research (more on this some other time), I found one I liked a lot &amp;ndash; the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/attractivechaos/plb/tree/master/sudoku&#34;&gt;Kudoku solver written in Java&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://attractivechaos.wordpress.com/2011/06/19/an-incomplete-review-of-sudoku-solver-implementations/&#34;&gt;attractive chaos&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how does one use a local jar file in a Clojure Project? Read on&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which Version of Java will Leiningen Run from an Emacs Shell</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2014/04/21/which-version-of-java-will-leiningen-run-from-an-emacs-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 13:51:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2014/04/21/which-version-of-java-will-leiningen-run-from-an-emacs-shell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been updating some of my projects to use the newly released Java 8. That includes many Clojure projects. These are just &amp;ldquo;flow of consciousness&amp;rdquo; debugging notes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paths with Spaces, I Give Up</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2013/08/08/paths-with-spaces-i-give-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2013/08/08/paths-with-spaces-i-give-up/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to look into the Pedestal framework for creating web-based applications in Clojure. However, one of the requirements is Leiningen 2.2.0 or greater. And, as I&amp;rsquo;ve written before, version 2.2 will not install on my system because of spaces in the path of the user home directory. (&amp;ldquo;C:\Users\David Clark&amp;rdquo; on my system.)
My user profile name is &amp;ldquo;david&amp;rdquo;. That&amp;rsquo;s what I use to sign on with. The fact that my home directory uses &amp;ldquo;David Clark&amp;rdquo; is an unfortunate result of how the computer was set up at the factory when I custom ordered it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Clojure Development Toolchain</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2013/05/21/the-clojure-development-toolchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 21:58:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2013/05/21/the-clojure-development-toolchain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things about &lt;a href=&#34;http://clojure.org/&#34;&gt;Clojure&lt;/a&gt; that is difficult for beginners is the process of creating and running programs. I would argue that it is more difficult than learning the language itself. There is no &amp;ldquo;one-button&amp;rdquo; provisioning system that would set up some sort of canonical development environment. This long post will talk about setting up Leiningen and Emacs to make a comfortable environment for developing in Clojure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>