<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Yo-Dave</title>
    <link>https://yo-dave.com/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Yo-Dave</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2011-2018, David D. Clark. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yo-dave.com/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>More Whinging about CloudAtCost</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2017/02/01/more-whinging-about-cloudatcost/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2017/02/01/more-whinging-about-cloudatcost/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written about my love/hate relationship with CloudAtCost before here and here. In essence, I like the low cost but hate the poor reliability.
At one time I had seven web sites up and running on servers bought from CloudAtCost, including this one. But over a period of weeks and months they all failed for one reason or another. Some of the failures could be fixed with a ticket to tech support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why This Blog Disappeared for a Few Days</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/12/08/why-this-blog-disappeared-for-a-few-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/12/08/why-this-blog-disappeared-for-a-few-days/</guid>
      <description>Those of you who visit this site regularly may have noticed that is has been down for a few days. Here&amp;rsquo;s why.
About a week ago, I attempted to reboot the server after applying a few updates. It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t come back up. As I&amp;rsquo;ve written before, this site is hosted on CloudAtCost. Sorry to say that it is a regular occurrence for servers not to reboot.
Usually, I can just file a ticket and get help in a day or so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Am So Over HD</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/10/02/i-am-so-over-hd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/10/02/i-am-so-over-hd/</guid>
      <description>Many years ago, back in 2009, during an infrequent upgrade of my desktop computer, I finally bought an HD monitor, actually, slightly better than HD at a resolution of 1920x1200 pixels. My reaction was along the lines of &amp;ldquo;Ooooh! Pretty!&amp;rdquo;. It was a big 27&amp;rdquo; unit. Easy to view, lots of screen real estate. Very clear text rendering.
I thought I was set forever.
Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve purchased a few Apple products with Retina displays.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>