<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>literate programming on Yo-Dave</title>
    <link>https://yo-dave.com/tags/literate-programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in literate programming on Yo-Dave</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2011-2018, David D. Clark. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yo-dave.com/tags/literate-programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaFX Still Not Ready?</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2013/12/29/javafx-still-not-ready/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2013/12/29/javafx-still-not-ready/</guid>
      <description>Just a short rant about JavaFX because I&#39;m pissed about it at the moment. I enjoy using it for the most part but it sometimes throws up surprising obstacles in otherwise routine work. The latest for me was an unexpected lack of a spinner control. There are alternatives in some open source projects, but, really? No spinners built in?
This is almost as gob-smacking weird as the lack of dialogs. (Ok, there are some dialogs, like for opening/saving files, but not much in the way of user-programmable dialogs built in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Data Grid Component -- A Personal Failing</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/09/22/java-data-grid-component-a-personal-failing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2011 08:06:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/09/22/java-data-grid-component-a-personal-failing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many of the programs I write need a way to enter and edit a two-dimensional grid of data in the user interface. Such a grid doesn&#39;t need to be a full-fledged spreadsheet, just provide flexible data entry and editing. Alas, there doesn&#39;t seem to be such a thing and I haven&#39;t created one that I&#39;m satisfied with.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathematica and MATLAB</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/02/11/mathematica-and-matlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2011 01:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/02/11/mathematica-and-matlab/</guid>
      <description>In some ways there are many similarities between Mathematica® and MATLAB®. From the simplest point of view, both are computer mathematics systems. I use both at work and, thus, am a wizard at neither. Let me expose my biases up front though. I like Mathematica enough that I have paid actual money to have a copy at home. With that bias in mind, let&#39;s look at some of the differences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Literate Programming</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2011/02/06/literate-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2011 01:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2011/02/06/literate-programming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever since &lt;a href=&#34;http://www-cs-faculty.stanford.edu/~uno/index.html&#34;&gt;Donald Knuth&lt;/a&gt; published &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.literateprogramming.com/knuthweb.pdf&#34;&gt;Literate Programming&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; back in 1984, I&#39;ve been a fan. Telling a computer how to run a program and helping a human understand it are two different but very necessary things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>