<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>writing on Yo-Dave</title>
    <link>https://yo-dave.com/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in writing on Yo-Dave</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2011-2018, David D. Clark. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://yo-dave.com/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>More Note-Taking Goodness - Collate</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2017/05/16/more-note-taking-goodness-collate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2017/05/16/more-note-taking-goodness-collate/</guid>
      <description>Last time, I wrote about some of the really nice note-taking apps available nowadays. Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve come across another great one I just had to tell you about: Collate.
It has just about everything I could want. I&amp;rsquo;ll let you read about all of its features on its web site, but some of the things I like most include:
 It&amp;rsquo;s cross-platform, capable of running on Windows, MacOS, and Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Embarrassment of Riches for Note-Taking</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2017/04/03/an-embarrassment-of-riches-for-note-taking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2017/04/03/an-embarrassment-of-riches-for-note-taking/</guid>
      <description>Ever since dumping Evernote, I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at alternative note-taking apps. I&amp;rsquo;ve been usingtiddlywiki, but, surprisingly, it has grown a bit slow. Probably from the sheer volume of notes that I&amp;rsquo;ve imported from Evernote. Maybe time to look some more?
I&amp;rsquo;ve also been writing a lot of program documentation in Markdown. I like the wiki format just fine, but it seems like Markdown can do more. Both markup languages have a plethora of dialects, usually incompatible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Favorite Pens</title>
      <link>https://yo-dave.com/2016/08/13/my-favorite-pens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yo-dave.com/2016/08/13/my-favorite-pens/</guid>
      <description>Sure, this is a technology site, but sometimes you have to get a little retro. That is the case for my preferences in note-taking. I tend to do a fair amount of writing into paper notebooks. To do that, I use a pen.
Fountain pens are pretty pieces of art, but too messy and fiddly. Ballpoints are OK, but feel a little harsh as you write. Roller balls are OK too, except the quality of the ink is a bit &amp;ldquo;smeary&amp;rdquo; for my tastes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>